Ever had one of those nights
你们经历过这样的夜晚吗?
that starts out like any other, but ends up being the best night of your life?
开始的时候平平常常 后来却永生难忘
Are you sitting comfortably? Then we'll begin.
大家坐好了吗? 我们要开始了
It was June the 22nd, 1990, our final day of school.
那是1990年6月22日 我们毕业的前一天
There was Oliver Chamberlain, Peter Page, Steven Prince, Andy Knightley and me.
有奥利弗・钱伯莱恩 皮特・佩奇 史蒂文・普林斯 安迪・奈特利 和我
They called me The King. Because my name's Gary King.
我们叫我老金 因为我的名字是加里・金
Ollie was funny, he fancied himself as a bit of a player, but really, he was all mouth.
奥利挺有意思 他自以为风流倜傥 但其实只会耍嘴皮子
We called him O-Man
我们叫他圈仔
because he had a birthmark on his forehead that looked like a six.
因为他额头上有个"6"形状的胎记
He loved it.
他喜欢那个胎记
Pete was the baby of the group.
皮特是我们的老幺
He wasn't the kind of kid we'd usually hang out with, but he was good for a laugh.
他不是我们常一起混的那种孩子 但是他很搞笑
And he was absolutely minted.
而且他是个土豪
Steve was a pretty cool guy. We jammed together, chased the girls.
史蒂文很酷 我们一起厮混 一起追女孩子
I think he saw us as rivals. Sweet, really.
我觉得他把我看做对手 但我们关系很好
And Andy. Andy was my wingman.
还有安迪 他是我的左膀右臂
The one guy I could rely on to back me up.
他是我最信任的人
He loved me, and I'm not being funny, but I loved him, too.
他爱我 而我也爱他 我没开玩笑
There was nothing we were gonna miss about school.
学校里的一切我们都毫不留恋
Maybe Mr. Shepherd.
或许有点舍不得谢菲尔德老师
He was definitely one of the good guys.
他确实是个好人
He used to ask me what I wanted to do with my life,
他曾经问过我以后有什么打算
I told him I just wanted to have a good time.
我告诉他 我只想找点乐子
He thought that was funny. It wasn't meant to be.
他说我们不正经 但其实不然
Not that night.
最起码那晚我们很认真
Newton Haven was our hometown. Our playground, our universe.
纽顿海文是我们的家乡 我们的游乐场 我们的宇宙
And that night it was the site of a heroic quest.
而在那一晚 那里是传奇探险的发生地
The aim? To conquer The Golden Mile.
目标? 完成豪饮马拉松
Twelve pubs along a legendary path of alcoholic indulgence.
十二家酒馆组成了我们的纵情畅饮之旅
There was The First Post, The Old Familiar,
它们是一号邮局 老相识
The Famous Cock, The Cross Hands, The Good Companions,
闻名雄鸡 交叉之手 好伙伴
The Trusty Servant, The Two Headed Dog, The Mermaid, The Beehive,
忠仆 双头狗 美人鱼 蜂窝
The King's Head, The Hole in the Wall...
国王之颅 墙洞...
All before reaching our destiny, The World's End.
但我们最终的目的地是 世界的尽头
We took my car into town.
我们开着我的车进了城
I called it The Beast because she was pretty hairy.
我管它叫野兽 因为它真的很猛
And so, our journey into manhood began.
我们的长大成人之旅由此开始
We were off. We didn't waste any time.
我们出发了 把握好每一寸光阴
We hit pub one and we hit it hard.
我们去了酒吧 大喝一场
There was drinking, there was fun, there was controversy,
我们醉了 我们笑了 我们针锋相对
there were ladies, there were shots, there was drama,
有小妞 有烈酒 有好戏看
and of course, there was drinking.
当然了 最重要的还是有酒喝
By pub five, we were feeling invincible
喝到第五家 我们觉得自己天下无敌
and decided to purchase some herbal refreshment
于是决定从那个叫绿圣人的人那里
from a man we called The Reverend Green.
买点带劲的草本物质
Pint six put O-Man out of commission, so we carried on without him.
喝到第六杯 圈仔不省人事 于是我们扔下他继续走
Good thing, I bumped into his sister in the next pub,
幸好如此 在下一间酒吧我遇到了他妹妹
we went into the disableds and I bumped into her again.
我们躲进残障洗手间 我又上了她一次
Sam tagged along for a while, but then I had to let her go.
山姆跟着我们了一会儿 但是我得甩掉她
I had another date that night and her name was Amber.
因为晚上我和安博尔还有个约会
Nine pints in and it was us against the world.
喝到第九杯 我们开始与世界为敌
Things got mental in The Beehive,
在蜂窝 事情有点大条
so we repaired to the bowls club
但我们在保龄球俱乐部弥补了回来
or as we liked to call it, The Smokehouse, which is when it all went fuck up.
我们喜欢叫它烟屋 那里的一切都很疯狂
Everyone got para and Pete chucked a whitey, so we had to bench him.
每个人都迷迷糊糊 皮特吸得脸发白 所以我们让他留下休息
In the end, we blew off the last three pubs and headed for the hills.
最后 我们喝过了最后三家酒馆 开始向山上进发
I remember sitting up there,
我记得坐在那里
blood on my knuckles, beer down my shirt, sick on my shoes,
我的指节还在流血 衣服上洒满啤酒 鞋子上沾着呕吐物
seeing the orange glow of a new dawn break
看着黎明的太阳冲破地平线
and knowing in my heart, life would never feel this good again.
我心里明白 生活再也不会像这一刻这样美妙
And you know what?
知道吗?
It never did.
确实如此
Thank you, Gary. That was very enlightening.
谢谢 加里 非常有启发性
Would anyone like to add anything or maybe challenge Gary?
还有人想说点什么吗 或是问加里个问题?
Are you disappointed?
你失望了吗?
- About what?  - That you didn't make it to The World's End?
- 失望什么?  - 你们最终没有到达世界的尽头?
No.
不
Just what is it that you want to do?
你们到底想要什么?
We want to be free!
我们想要自由!
We want to be free to do what we want to do!
我们想要为所欲为!
And we want to get loaded. And we want to have a good time,
我们想喝醉 想玩个痛快
And that's what we're going to do.
我们就是这样
We're going to have a good time.
想要玩个痛快
We're going to have a party.
我们要举办一场派对
世界的尽头
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 初见 咳嗽的小鱼 RK翔 汐颜 Mabb
校对: Mabb
Just what is it that you want to do?
你们到底想要做什么?
And we want to get loaded. And we want to have a good time,
我们想喝醉 想要玩个痛快
- She's a beauty.  - Yeah, but she's no Beast.
- 它真美  - 但它不是野兽
Hello, Peter.
你好 皮特
Jesus! Gary?
天啊! 加里?
The once and future King.
永远的老金
Were you outside my house this morning?
今天早上是你在我家外面晃吗?
No.
不是
I could have sworn I saw you on my street.
我敢肯定我看到你在我家门口的大街上
I've never been to Bishop's Gardens.
我从来没去过毕肖普花园
How you doing, man?
你还好吗 哥们?
- I'm well. You?  - Yeah, never better.
- 还好 你呢?  - 我很好
- How is, uh...  - Vanessa?
- 她怎么样...  - 你说维尼萨?
- No. Your wife?  - Vanessa.
- 不 我说的是你妻子?  - 她叫维尼萨
- Yeah. How's she?  - She's good.
- 好吧 她怎么样?  - 她很好
- Have you had sex yet?  - We have two children.
- 你们上床了吗?  - 我们都有两个孩子了
Ooh, twice. Get you, fuck machine.
哦 上了两次 你这个大色狼
We haven't changed, have we?
我们一点没变 是吧?
What is he doing here?
他来这里干嘛?
It's all right, Dad. We're fine.
没事的 爸爸
Hi, Mr. P.
嗨 P叔
So, Gary, how can I help you?
加里 有什么能帮你的吗?
- He looks well.  - Are you looking to buy a car?
- 你老爹还挺精神  - 你要买车?
Uh... No. I'm afraid the end is nigh.
呃... 不是 我们已经很接近尽头了
- What?  - The World's End.
- 什么?  - 世界的尽头
What do you mean?
什么意思?
You know what I mean. One night. Five guys. Twelve pubs.
你懂我的意思的 一晚上 五个人 喝遍十二家酒吧
Let battle commence.
让酒瓶飞一会
You want to try that again?
你还想再来一次?
Yeah, isn't that something you've always wanted?
这难道这不是你一直梦寐以求的吗?
- Not particularly. No.  - Look. Peter.
- 不是  - 听着 皮特
We didn't make it before, but this time, we're gonna see it through to the bitter end.
那时我们没有成功 但这次我们一定要到达尽头
Or lager end.
一探究竟
- We?  - Yeah, the whole gang.
- 我们?  - 嗯 所有人
- Even Andy?  - Why wouldn't Andy be coming?
- 安迪也去?  - 安迪为什么不去?
- Well, I thought that after the accident...  - Notan issue. He's in.
- 我以为那场事故之后...  - 没那回事 他来的
What we wanna know is are you?
我们只想知道 你来不来?
I'd have to check with Vanessa.
我得问一下维尼萨
- Who's Vanessa?  - My wife.
- 维尼萨是谁  - 我太太
Since when have you had to check with your wife?
从什么时候开始你听老婆的话了?
Since we got married.
从我们结婚开始
Oh, come on, man, don't you miss it?
别这样 哥们 你不怀念那些日子吗?
The laughs, the camaraderie, the fights,
欢笑 兴奋 打架
the hangovers so fierce it feels like your head is full of ants.
醉得好像脑袋要炸掉一样
Maybe the first two.
前两个比较怀念
It begins. What's your new number?
好了 你的新号码是什么?
Same one I've had for 10 years.
我十年来一直用的那个号码啊
Yeah. What's that one?
嗯 号码是什么?
This entire row here, they'll all have dormer windows above the front elevation.
这一排房子屋顶上有天窗
Who's the helmet without an helmet?
那是谁没戴安全帽?
That's Gary King.
是加里・金
Knock, knock.
咚咚咚
What are you doing here, Gary?
你来这里干嘛 加里?
You're supposed to say, "Who's there?"
你应该说"谁在敲门?"
I can see who's there. It's you.
我可以看到你
I like what you've done with the place. Bit draughty.
我喜欢你盖的房子 通风不错
- How's Selina?  - We divorced 10 years ago.
- 瑟琳娜还好吗?  - 我们十年前就离婚了
Yeah, I know, just wondered how she was.
我知道 我就是问问她好不好
She's doing very well, apparently.
很显然 她过得不错
Have you got anyone else on the go?
你有下一个目标了吗?
Yeah, I do, as it happens. She's a fitness instructor. Twenty-six.
是的 她是个健身教练 二十六岁
Pedophile. I'm kidding. I'd love to meet her sometime.
恋童癖 我开玩笑的 有机会我想见见她
No. Why are you here?
别了 你来这里干嘛?
Haven't you heard? We're getting the band back together.
你没听说吗? 我们要东山再起
I'm not your bass player anymore.
我早都不玩贝斯了
No, I mean we're getting the boys back together.
我是说兄弟联盟要东山再起
We can get the band back together as well if you want.
如果你希望 乐队也可以重组
No, we can't. You sold my guitar to buy drugs.
不行了 你用我的吉他换毒品了
I've always wondered, what's that thing over the door called?
我一直都很好奇 门上面的那个是什么?
That's a lintel.
是门梁
So, the plan is, we're going to go back to Newton Haven,
计划是这样的 我们回到纽顿海文
we are gonna do The Golden Mile
去完成豪饮马拉松
and this time, we are gonna make it to The World's End.
这次我们一定要到达世界的尽头
Everybody's in.
大家都来
What, even Andy?
安迪也去?
Oh, you better believe it, big balls.
一点没错
- Andy is going drinking with you?  - With us.
- 安迪答应和你们一起喝酒?  - 和我们一起
Think about it, go back to the old town, sink a few pints...
考虑一下吧 回到老地方 大伙一起喝点酒
- Twelve pints.  - Yeah.
- 喝十二杯  - 嗯
- Twelve pints is insane.  - I know!
- 喝十二杯太疯狂了  - 我知道!
What is this all about, Gary?
为什么要这么做 加里?
It's about closure, you know.
因为要有始有终
Why should getting older affect something as important as friendship?
为什么岁月会磨灭我们珍贵的友情?
- A lot's changed since then, Oliver.  - Right.
- 我们都变了很多 奥利弗  - 是的
This is our chance to take stock.
我们可以好好叙叙旧
A stock take? You make it sound so much fun.
叙叙旧? 听你说倒是挺有意思的
Come on, O-Man. Isn't that something you'd like?
别这样 圈仔 你难道不想那样吗?
What I'd really like is for you to take your DMs off the sofa.
我只想让你别躺在沙发上
Look. If you're worried about me, don't be. All right?
听着 如果你担心我 大可不必
I'm here to tell you that Gary King is back on the horse.
我是来告诉你 加里・金放马回来了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. You're back on the horse?
哇 哇 你放马回来了?
No, I mean I'm back on the bike.
好吧 我是骑自行车回来的
- What is bike?  - What do you mean?
- 自行车是什么意思?  - 怎么了?
- What is bike slang for?  - Bicycle.
- 自行车有什么内涵?  - 就是自行车
- I'm lost.  - Don't be.
- 我晕了  - 别这样
- Okay.  - Listen.
- 好吧  - 听着
This is our chance to finally finish what we started.
我们终于有机会完成心愿了
Come on, man, it'll be fucking mental!
来吧 哥们 疯狂一回!
I think we're all done. So...
我们看完了...
How do you like the property?
你们觉得这处房子怎么样?
- Yeah. It's amazing.  - Amazing location.
- 还不错  - 位置多好啊
- Fantastic.  - Fantastic aspects.
- 很棒  - 确实很棒
- It's just...  - It's just a little bit out of our price range.
- 但有点...  - 有点超出我们的预算了
He'll knock some off for you. What's it down for?
他会给你们优惠的 你们能出多少?
- 1.2 million.  - Fuck off!
- 一百二十万  - 去死吧!
You have my card.
你们有我名片
Gary, WTF?
加里 搞什么?
It's good to see you, too, O-Man.
我也很想你 圈仔
- Please don't call me O-Man.  - Sure.
- 别叫我圈仔 拜托了  - 好吧
- Hey, how's your sister?  - She's fine.
- 嘿 你妹妹怎么样了?  - 她很好
- She talk about me?  - No.
- 她常提起我吗?  - 没有
So, Friday, we'll all go down together.
周五我们一起出发
Make a road trip of it, I'll drive.
来个公路旅行 我来开车
Don't think I can. I think I've got a doctor's appointment.
我好像不行 我约了医生
Yeah, you do. With Dr. Ink!
是啊 你约了"醉好"的医生!
- You know, Dr. Ink?  - Yeah. "Drink." I get it.
- 你知道吗?  - "醉好"的医生 我听到了
Come on. It wouldn't be the same without the O-Man.
别这样 没有圈仔怎么行
Jesus.
天啊
You can see the guys, see how they're doing. Tell them how you're doing.
你能见到大家伙 看看他们都过得怎么样 也说说你过得怎么样
You never know, you might make it to the end this time.
这次我们或许能到达尽头
- And Andy's definitely coming?  - Yeah.
- 安迪肯定会去?  - 嗯
- Andy Knightley?  - Totes.
- 安迪・奈特利?  - 没错
And you convinced him how?
你已经跟他说好了?
- Mr. Knightley.  - Felicity.
- 奈特利先生  - 有事吗
You have a friend here to see you.
有位朋友想见您
No, I don't.
我不想见他
- This is a bit grown up, isn't it?  - Yup.
- 真是有模有样 对吧?  - 嗯
- Saw the boys the other day.  - Mmm-hmm.
- 前几天碰到哥几个了  - 嗯
O-Man, Stevie-Baby, the Petertron.
圈仔 史蒂文 还有皮特
Yeah, I remember the names of our childhood friends, Gary.
发小的名字我没忘记 加里
We had ourselves a little idea.
我们有个小点子
Did you now?
是吗?
Yeah. We're going to go back to Newton Haven.
我们想回到纽顿海文
- Why?  - For some unfinished business.
- 为什么?  - 为了未完成的事业
That's a joke, right?
你在开玩笑吗?
- Five guys. Twelve pubs. Fifty pints.  - Sixty pints.
- 五个哥们 十二家酒馆 五十杯啤酒  - 是六十杯
Steady on, you fucking alky.
是吗 你这个大酒鬼
I haven't had a drink for 16 years, Gary.
我十六年来滴酒不沾 加里
You must be thirsty then.
那你肯定很想喝点
We can go back, see the guys, chew the fat, it'll be just like it always was,
我们可以回去 大伙一起吃吃饭 就像以前一样
except this time we're going to finish this thing once and for all.
但这一次我们不达目的誓不罢休
- You have a very selective memory, Gary.  - Thanks.
- 你还真是选择性记忆啊 加里  - 好吧
You remember the Friday nights.
你只记得周五晚上
I remember the Monday mornings.
而我还记着周一早上
Yeah, that's why we're going back on a Friday.
所以我们选周五晚上回去呀
Why do you think none of us live in Newton Haven anymore?
你知道为什么我们全都离开纽顿海文吗?
- I don't know.  - Because it's a black hole. It's boring.
- 不知道  - 因为那是个黑洞 乏味无聊
It always was and it always will be.
过去现在将来一直如此
It's only boring because we're not there.
因为我们不在那里 所以才无聊的
- It's pointless arguing with you.  - Exactly. So come.
- 对牛弹琴  - 没错 所以你就来吧
I'm picking everybody up from High Wycombe station, Friday, 3:00 sharp.
我星期五三点整到海威科姆车站接你们
No, Gary.
不 加里
Oh, God, why? Have you got to check with your missus?
天啊 怎么了? 你也要问问你太太吗?
No, actually, I don't have to check with my missus.
不 我不用问我太太
- What are you doing?  - I'm showing you the door.
- 你干嘛?  - 这是出去的门
Is it a door? It doesn't have a lintel.
这是门吗? 怎么没有门梁
And it's glass. So is it a window or is it a door?
它是玻璃的 所以这是窗还是门?
Maybe it's a windoor. You can have that.
或者是个门窗 这样就行了
Please leave, Gary.
请走吧 加里
All right. All right.
好吧 好吧
￡600, wasn't it?
600英镑 对吧?
- Oh, urn, I thought you should know.  - What?
- 我应该告诉你  - 什么?
Mum died.
我妈去世了
- When?  - Couple of weeks ago.
- 什么时候?  - 几个礼拜前
The big cancer.
是癌症
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
She just always really liked you, you know.
她很喜欢你
Got me thinking about the old days.
她走了 让我想起了以前
Particularly that night, you know, because we were so happy.
特别是那天晚上 因为那时我们真的很开心
And, you know, I love the boys like brothers,
这些哥们和我亲如兄弟
but when all's said and done, you're the best friend I ever had.
但是话说回来 你才是我最好的朋友
It was good to see you, mate.
能见到你真好 哥们
Pete?
皮特?
- Steven.  - Thank God.
- 史蒂文  - 太好了
I had a horrible feeling I was going to be the only one here.
我还担心只有我一个人会来呢
I reckon that's not the last horrible feeling you're gonna have today, mate.
我敢打赌肯定有更糟的事情等着你
This can't be happening. Can it?
不会吧?
You said it. What the hell are we doing here?
说不准 我们来这是干嘛的?
What we always did.
我们总是这样
Follow Gary King into almost certain oblivion.
跟在加里・金屁股后面到处逛
Hello, Steven.
你好 史蒂文
You all right, mate?
你还好吧 哥们?
- Pete.  - Hi, mate.
- 皮特  - 嗨 哥们
Didn't we decide to stop calling him Fearless Leader somewhere around 1992?
我们不是从1992年开始就不叫他无敌领袖了吗?
Old habits die hard.
真是本性难移
They'll be putting that on Gary's tombstone.
他们会把这几个字刻在加里的墓碑上
No, they won't. You know he'll outlive us all.
不会的 他肯定活的比我们长
That'll be funny if it wasn't true.
要是那样就有意思了
- Hang on a sec.  - What?
- 等一下  - 怎么了?
I'm just trying to decide which of us is the biggest idiot for coming.
我想知道我们究竟谁是最傻的那一个
Maybe he had an accident. Oh, sorry, Andy.
也许他出车祸了 不好意思 安迪
- Sorry.  - No, no, no. It's fine.
- 抱歉  - 没事 没事
I think Gary having an accident
我觉得加里要是真出了车祸
would actually be the best outcome for all of us, including Gary.
这对我们都好 对他自己也好
Unbelievable.
没搞错吧
Oh, yes.
来吧
Look at these cunts.
看看这些贱人
- You're late.  - No, I'm not.
- 你迟到了  - 没有
Yeah, you are. You said 3:00. It's almost 4:00.
你有 你说的是三点 现在都快四点了
Yeah, 3 for 4.
对 不三不四嘛
You know your problem, Gary? You're never wrong.
你知道吗 加里? 你从来不肯低头认错
How is that a problem?
这有什么不对吗?
I can't believe you bought another Granada Mark II.
真不敢相信 你又买了一辆格拉纳达二代
What do you mean?
什么意思?
This looks exactly like the car I sold you in 1989.
它和我89年卖给你的那辆一模一样
This is the car you sold me in 1989. Best 300 quid I ever spent.
这就是1989年你卖给我的那辆 300英镑真是物超所值
- This is The Beast?  - Yeah.
- 这是野兽?  - 嗯
Pretty much. I mean, she's had a bit of work done.
差不多吧 我把她修整了一下
I had to replace the brakes, suspension, exhaust, seats, wheels,
换了刹车 悬架 排气管 座椅 轮胎
paneling, carburetor, manifold, the whole engine, really, mirrors, headlamps.
嵌板 化油器 分电盘 全套发动机 后视镜 还有头灯
Other than that, she's the same old motor.
但除此之外 它还是原来那样车
You could almost say an antique.
它可以算是古董了
Well, then let's get this antique on the roadshow.
我们开着这个古董上路表演吧
Come on, you bellends. We're going to be late.
来吧 巡回演出 别晚了
And we're back. Just like the Five Musketeers.
我们回来了 就像五个火枪手
Three Musketeers, isn't it?
不是三个火枪手吗?
Four if you count D'Artagnan,
算上达达尼昂是四个
Well, nobody knows how many there were, really, do they, Pete?
没人知道他们到底有几个人 是吧 皮特?
You do know that The Three Musketeers is a fiction, right?
"三个火枪手"是部小说 你知道的吧?
Written by Alexandre Dumas?
大仲马写的?
A lot of people are saying that about the Bible these days.
现在很多人老这么念叨圣经
What, that it was written by Alexandre Dumas?
怎么了 难不成也是大仲马写的?
Don't be daft, Steve, it was written by Jesus.
别傻了 史蒂文 是耶稣写的
Oh. Anyway, five sounds much better.
噢 随便啦 五个听起来顺口些
I think they missed a trick only having three.
我觉得他就弄三个主角有点失误
'Cause you'd have five, then two could've died and they'd still have three left.
如果是五个人 可以牺牲掉两个 最后还是剩下他们仨
- Are we there yet?  - Let's do this!
- 我们到了吗?  - 出发吧!
Soup Dragons! I remember this one.
汤龙乐队! 我记得这首歌
I put this on a tape for you, didn't I?
我还录了盘带子给你 记得吗?
Yeah, this is it.
没错 现在放的就是
- This is the tape?  - Yeah, yeah! Look, look.
- 就是这盘带子?  - 是啊 没错! 瞧瞧
- Where did you find it?  - It was in the tape player.
- 你在哪找到的?  - 一直在磁带机里啊
Oh, look. Is anyone hungry?
噢 看那 有人饿了吗?
I need a piss actually.
我想去尿尿
This is a long piss.
他去了好久啊
If it is a piss.
尿的话是挺久的
- Might be a little...  - Poo.
- 也许还...  - 拉屎
How is that a poo?
怎么就成拉屎了呢?
- Still work for your old man, Pete?  - Yeah. I'm a partner now.
- 还给你家老头子打工呢 皮特?  - 是的 我现在是合伙人了
You?
你混的怎样?
Yeah, started my own firm in '98. Got bought out in '05.
89年创业 05年把公司卖了
I'm happier, though. It's less stress.
不过开心多了 没那么大压力
- Ollie?  - Property.
- 奥利你呢?  - 还在卖房子
I co-manage a boutique estate agency in North London.
我管伦敦北区的高档房屋中介
Very competitive.
这行竞争很激烈
- Is it family law you're in, Andy?  - Corporate.
- 还在处理家庭法相关案子吗 安迪?  - 换企业法了
Does anyone know what Gary's doing?
有人知道加里现在做什么吗?
He's playing Need For Speed. Over there.
他在玩极品飞车呢 就在那
Come on, come on, come on!
快 快 快啊!
He hasn't changed, has he?
他一点都没变 对吗?
I don't know. He did finally pay me back that ￡600.
我不知道 他倒是把欠我的600镑还了
- Really? He borrowed ￡200 off me.  - And me.
- 真的吗? 他找我借了200镑呢  - 还有我
I can't believe it. I can't believe you'd do that!
我不敢相信 这种事你也做得出来!
Oh! Of course I can.
噢! 必须的好不好
It's just robbing Peter to pay Paul.
抢皮特的钱还给保罗
No, I borrowed it from Peter to pay you. I still owe Paul.
错 我借皮特钱还给了你 我还欠着保罗呢
Oh, shit.
噢 爽啊
Newton Haven.
纽顿海文
Take a moment to look upon it in its original colors, boys, for tonight we paint it red.
花点时间记住它原来的模样 兄弟们 今晚我们要给它改头换面了
Oh, no, no, no. Shit.
噢 不要 不 不 不 糟糕
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
妈的 妈的
Fuck, fuck.
妈的
Oh, no, it's okay, I did it all in the services.
噢 不 没事的 我常在服务区这么干
Know why I pulled you over, sir?
知道我为什么拦你吗 先生?
Was the music too loud?
音乐太吵吗?
- Your left brake light is faulty.  - Oh!
- 你左侧刹车灯坏了  - 噢!
The old brake lights! So called because they're always breaking.
老掉牙的刹车灯! 难怪叫刹车灯 因为动不动就歇菜
I'll get that sorted out, Officer.
警官 我一定会修好的
- Can I see your license, sir?  - Yup.
- 能给我看看你的驾照吗 先生?  - 好的
Ah!
啊!
You know what? It's in my wallet.
完蛋了? 在我钱包里
And I left that at the bloody gym!
钱包落在健身房了!
- Any other form of identification?  - No, it's all in my sports bag.
- 有什么其他证件吗?  - 没有 都在我包里
That's bloody typical, isn't it? Um...
这种状况挺常见的 对吗? 嗯...
I'll give you my name and address, you can run me through the old system.
我把名字和地址告诉你 你能在系统里查到
Go on then.
说吧
It's Peter Page.
我叫皮特・佩奇
48 Bishop's Gardens, London, N2 T12.
住在伦敦北区 48号 毕肖普花园
- Jesus, Gary! WTF?  - Why did you give him my name?
- 天啊 加里! 搞毛线啊?  - 你干嘛说我的名字?
I'm not gonna give him my name, am I?
我又不可能告诉他我的 对吧?
Suppose I get done by the police?
你想让警察找我麻烦?
You won't get done by the police.
不会有警察找你的
Gary, he will check the number plate against his name!
加里 警察会发现人车对不上号!
I know. Why do you think I gave him Pete's name?
我知道 所以我告诉他我是皮特啊
Jesus Christ, Gary, I own a car showroom. I am a junior partner.
天啊 加里 我有个租车行 而且刚入股
This is...
真是...
Just trust me.
相信我就是了
So, Mr. Page, what brings you to Newton Haven?
那么 皮特先生 你为什么来纽顿海文?
Well, we're all from here. We're just back to see the sights.
我们过去都住这 回来看看风景
Have a crack at the old Golden Mile.
重温儿时回忆
Might get a bit messy.
也许还会捣点乱
Well, you make sure you get that brake light fixed
这么说吧 首先你得保证把刹车灯修好
and you might want to do an emissions test, too.
可能还得做个尾气标准测试
Oh, and, Peter.
噢 还有 皮特
Don't make too much mess.
记住别闹大了
We won't!
不会的!
Hmm.
嗯
I don't understand.
我搞不懂
It's simple, Pete.
很简单 皮特
The car's still registered to you, it has been since 1989.
从1989年起 这辆车就一直在你名下
But I've moved three times since then.
但那以后我都搬过三次家了
I know, I changed the log book.
我知道 我改了记录
Where do you think all those points came from?
不然我哪来分给警察扣?
Jesus. You guys need to relax.
天啊 大伙都放松点
Do you know how much trouble you could get into?
你知道你会惹出一堆麻烦吗?
Do you know how much trouble I'm already in?
你都不知道我已经一团糟了?
What's that supposed to mean?
你这话什么意思?
Hey. What the hell is this? Why are we even here?
嘿 这究竟是怎么回事? 我们为什么来这里?
We are here to get annihilated.
一起全军覆没
Have you got any plans for dinner at all?
晚上有什么想吃的吗?
Tonight, we will be partaking of a liquid repast
今天晚上 我们要完成豪饮马拉松
as we wend our way up The Golden Mile.
今天晚上酒就是我们的晚餐
Commencing with an inaugural tankard at The First Post,
先去一号邮局 来一大桶啤酒
then onto The Old Familiar, The Famous Cock, The Cross Hands,
然后去老相识 闻名雄鸡 交叉之手
The Good Companions, The Trusty Servant,
好伙伴 忠仆
The Two Headed Dog, The Mermaid, The Beehive, The King's Head
双头猎狗 美人鱼 蜂窝 国王之颅
and The Hole in the Wall for a measure of the same.
然后墙洞 和上回路线一致
All before the last bittersweet pint in that most fateful terminus,
直到宿命的终点站 喝光最后一滴酒
The World's End.
世界的尽头
Leave a light on, good lady,
为我们留盏灯 夫人
for though we may return with a twinkle in our eyes,
虽然我们回来时 眼神还透着兴奋劲
we will, in truth, be blind drunk.
但我敢打包票 全都烂醉如泥了
Come on!
来吧!
- Until 1840...  - Fucking hell.
- 直到1840年...  - 去他妈的
this building was the site of Newton Haven's first post office.
这里还是纽顿海文第一家邮局
Until an enterprising business fellow decided that
一个进取的生意人发现
far from befitting the sending and receiving of mail
相比用来收发邮件
it was perhaps better suited as a humble taproom
这儿更适合做酒吧
where a weary traveler might get matted. Come on.
给疲倦的旅人歇歇脚 快进来吧
Ah!
啊!
It's like déjà vu.
简直是昨日重现
I don't remember this at all. Has it been refurbished?
我一点印象都没有 这里重装了吗?
Been bought by a chain, hasn't it?
被连锁店收购了 对吗?
Part of that nationwide initiative to rob
全国性提案的一部分
small, charming pubs of any discernible character.
同化那些个性的小酒吧
Starbucking, man. It's happening everywhere.
好比星巴克 哥们 这种事很常见
Can't take away that smell, though.
不过 味道还和过去一样
I'm sure they tried.
我相信他们尽力了
- Good evening, Raymondo. The prodigal sons return.  - Eh?
- 晚上好 雷蒙多 浪子们回头了  - 什么?
Who's on the guest list tonight?
今晚都有什么嘉宾?
- Come again?  - The guest ales.
- 你说什么?  - 宾客名单
We, sir, are doing The Golden Mile and you have
我们几个 先生 我们来重温美好时光了
the honor of drawing first blood.
你有幸成为第一位见证者
- What do you recommend?  - There's one. Crowning Glory.
- 有什么推荐的?  - 有一个还不错 至高荣耀
- Rather fitting.  - How's that?
- 再合适不过了  - 怎么说?
- I'm Gary King.  - What?
- 我叫加里・金  - 什么?
- So tell me more.  - About what?
- 多说点  - 关于什么?
Crowning Glory. Is it nutty? Is it foamy? Is it happy?
至高荣耀 带果仁吗? 气泡多吗? 会让人开心吗?
Does it have a surprisingly fruity note which lingers on the tongue?
是不是有种特殊的果味 会留香唇齿间?
- Hmm. It's beer.  - Hmm.
- 嗯 啤酒而已  - 好吧
We'll have five of those, please.
我们要五杯
No. Sorry. Can we have four of those and a tap water, please?
不 不好意思 只要四杯外加杯水 谢谢
What?
什么?
I don't believe this,
不敢相信
a man of your legendary prowess drinking fucking rain.
猛男居然喝白开水
It's like seeing a lion eating some hummus.
简直和狮子吃豆泥一样荒唐
- That doesn't make any sense.  - I know it doesn't make any sense.
- 没道理  - 的确没道理
You seriously have a problem with me not drinking, after what happened?
发生了那样的事 你还计较我不喝酒?
- I don't, but King Arthur does!  - Oh, this'll be good.
- 我不知道 不过亚瑟王知道!  - 噢 没准有点用
What's King Arthur got to do with it?
亚瑟王会怎么做?
Do you honestly think that King Arthur came back from the Battle of Hastings,
从黑斯廷斯战场归来后 你觉得亚瑟王
- fucking rocked up at Arthur's Castle...  - Camelot.
- 会他妈躲进城堡...  - 卡米洛特
walked up to the bar and went,
走向酒吧然后说
"Hello. Could I have a tap water?"
"你好 给我来杯自来水?"
No, because they didn't have running water in Arthurian times.
不会 在亚瑟王的时代 根本就没有自来水
Exactly. He would have had a mead. The King Arthur of beers.
说的没错 他会要杯蜂蜜酒 亚瑟王的啤酒
And I'm less of a man because I choose to drink water?
我喝水就不是男人了吗?
Well, it's a bit "ooh ducky", innit?
的确有点娘 不是吗?
That's not very PC, Gary.
加里 这么说很不友好
Get out of the '90s, Pete.
别整老一套 皮特
There's nothing "ooh ducky" about being teetotal,
戒酒一点也不娘
about walking into a pub after a rugby match
尤其是在橄榄球赛结束后 走进酒吧
and ordering a tap water at a bar packed full of big ugly bastards wearing warpaint.
往脸上涂着油彩混球们中间一站 然后要一杯白开水
That, my friend, takes confidence, yeah? I'm talking balls
那可是需要极大自信的 朋友 我有的是胆量
You said it, poof.
谁信啊 傻瓜
I don't know if you're aware of this, Gary, but we are not teenagers anymore.
我不知道你意识到没有 加里 我们已经不是小孩子了
And God forbid you ever have children, because if...
上帝是不会允许你有孩子的 因为...
I might have kids.
我可能有孩子
Then you had better be ready to take responsibility...
那你最好做好负责任的准备...
No. I mean I might have kids.
不 我是说我可能真有孩子
You remember Karen Eggerton, who I fucked?
还记得卡伦・艾格顿吗 我们睡过?
She was two weeks late when her parents emigrated to Normandy.
他们家移民去诺曼底的时候 她月经迟到了两周
I never heard from her again. She might have had a baby.
我和她再也没联系过了 她也许有孩子了
Imagine that? A French kid.
想象一下? 法国孩子
It's pointless arguing with you.
简直是对牛弹琴
To kids. Wherever they may be.
为孩子干杯 不管他们如何
- Kids.  - Kids.
- 为了孩子  - 孩子
Drink up. Let's Boo-Boo.
干杯 我们嘘嘘吧
"Boo-Boo". What is that?
"嘘嘘" 什么意思?
You remember, "Let's Boo-Boo."
你记得 "我们嘘嘘吧"
You know, from Mr. Shepherd's classroom, it said on the wall,
谢菲尔德先生的课 墙上写着
"Exit, pursued by a bear," you know, from that Shakespeare play?
"快逃 熊追上来了" 还记得吗 莎士比亚的剧本?
- A Winter's Tale.  - Yeah. What was it called?
- 冬日絮语  - 没错 叫什么来着?
A Winter's Tale. That's it.
冬日絮语 就叫这个
And if we needed to make a quick getaway, we'd say, "Exit, pursued by a bear,"
所以如果我们要赶紧撤 就会说 "快逃 熊追上来了"
and then it was, "Exit, pursued by Yogi Bear,"
后来就成了 "快逃 瑜伽熊追上来了"
and then it was just, "Let's Yogi and Boo-Boo,"
然后是 "练练瑜伽嘘嘘吧"
and then, "Let's Boo-Boo."
最后就成了 "我们嘘嘘吧"
- So you're saying we should go?  - Yeah. it's shit here, isnit?
- 你的意思是 我们撤?  - 没错 这就是重点 对不对?
Ah!
啊!
The Old Familiar. Now this is a pub.
老相识 这才是酒吧
Yes. This is more like it.
是啊 和第一个差不多
Like déjà vu.
昨日重现
David, my man, have you heard the news? Gary King is back in town.
戴维 哥们 听到消息了吗? 加里・金回镇上了
Who's he?
他是谁?
How was the funeral, Gary?
葬礼怎么样 加里?
Your mum's funeral?
你妈妈的葬礼?
It's difficult to put into words.
难以用言语形容
But if I had to choose three, I would say,
不过用三个词的话 我会说
"Really, really sad."
"真的 真的 难过"
Oh, no, that's two, isn't it?
噢 不 这是两个词 对不对?
How about, "Really, very sad"?
这样吧 "真的 非常 难过"
It's a shame, she was a good woman.
真遗憾 你妈妈很好
I really liked your mum.
我真的很喜欢你妈妈
Me, too, mate. Me, too.
我也是 伙计 我也是
- Hello.  - Hello, mate.
- 喂  - 你好 伙计
Are you here?
你到了吗?
Yeah, I've been here for ages. What are you talking about?
是啊 我在这待了好久了 你说什么呢?
You get lost on the ring road again?
又在环岛公路上迷路了?
This is Newton Haven.
这里是纽顿海文
- What time are you meeting The Twins?  - Twins?
- 打算几点去见双胞胎?  - 双胞胎?
We're all at The Old Familiar. Come by if you want.
我们在老相识 没事的话过来吧
Yeah, he is. Okay. See you soon.
没错 他也在 好的 待会见
Who was that, O-Man?
和谁说话呢 圈仔?
Don't call me O-Man, Gary. If you must know it was Sam.
别叫我圈仔 加里 如果你非要知道的话 是山姆
- Sam's here?  - Sam's here?
- 山姆在这?  - 山姆在这?
Is there a fucking echo in here? Yes, Sam's here.
我听见回音了吗? 没错 山姆在这
She's down from Manchester. We're driving to Mum's tomorrow.
她从曼彻斯特过来 明天我们一起去妈妈那里
What, and she's coming here?
什么 她要来这?
- Calm down, Steve, I saw her first.  - Jesus Christ, not this again.
- 冷静点 史蒂文 我先看到她的  - 天啊 又来了
Are you fucking kidding me? I saw her first.
开什么玩笑? 是我先看到她的
You really have a selective memory, don't you?
你有选择性记忆症 对吧?
Somebody else was saying that.
是有人这么说
- Me.  - No. I would have remembered.
- 我说的  - 不 你说的话我肯定记得
I told you I had a thing about Sam
我告诉过你我喜欢山姆
and you proceeded to try and get in her pants at every opportunity.
可一有机会你就想上她
Guys, please.
兄弟们 拜托
You only liked her after you found out I liked her!
因为我喜欢她所以你才喜欢她!
That's right, because you did the school play.
没错 因为你在学校演话剧
- Cabaret.  - Cabaret. Because she was in it.
- 卡巴莱歌舞表演  - 卡巴莱 因为她也出演了
And she wore those fishnet stockings and you got a big boner on stage.
她穿了网袜 结果你在台上硬了
Jesus Christ.
天啊
Doesn't matter anyway, she always had a massive wide on for Adrian Keane.
无所谓了 她随时恭候阿德里安・基恩呢
I hated that prick.
我讨厌那混蛋
Can we not talk about my sister in relation to,
能不能不要提到我妹妹 就说起
A, massive wide ons, B, Steven's erect penis?
A 随时恭候 B 史蒂文的老二?
All right.
好的
- Is she still fit, though?  - I'm not answering that.
- 她还是前凸后翘吗 说真的?  - 我不会告诉你的
Is she, though?
她是不是呀?
- Am I what?  - Fit.
- 我是什么?  - 苗条健康
- Hello, Sam.  - Steven? You've grown, haven't you?
- 你好 山姆  - 史蒂文? 你变化真大啊?
- Yeah, sideways.  - You look fantastic.
- 没错 横向发展  - 你看起来真棒
Steroids.
胆固醇太多
Andy, longtime.
安迪 好久没见了
- Hi, Pete.  - Hi, Sam.
- 你好 皮特  - 你好 山姆
All right, big brother?
好啦 老弟?
Gary.
加里
Willkommen. Bienvenue. Welcome.
欢迎 欢迎 欢迎
Sam. Would you like a drink?
山姆 一起喝杯酒吗?
Hey, Steve. She's just got here. Come on.
嘿 史蒂文 她才刚到这 拜托
Sam. Would you like a drink?
山姆 一起喝杯酒吗?
- I'll have a vodka tonic, thanks, Steven.  - Sure.
- 给我来杯伏特加汤力 谢谢 史蒂文  - 好的
- I'm just going to nip to the loo.  - Cool.
- 我先去下洗手间  - 好的
Nature calls.
上厕所了
- What are you doing?  - What are you doing?
- 你要做什么?  - 你要做什么?
- I'm going to the toilet.  - Well, then, so am I.
- 我要去洗手间  - 好吧 我也是
Gary! You are out of your mind!
加里! 你疯了吗!
What are you talking about? You gave me the sign.
你说什么呢? 是你先给我暗示的
- What sign?  - You went to the toilet.
- 什么暗示?  - 你去厕所
Gary, are you serious? I haven't seen you in 20 years.
加里 你玩真的呀? 我都二十年没见你了
Do you really think I'm going to have sex with you in the ladies' toilet?
你不会真以为我要在女厕所和你做爱?
Well, the disableds is out of order.
好吧 残疾人用的厕所坏了
- Gary. What happened?  - I don't know,
- 加里 发生了什么事?  - 我不知道
maybe one of them put too many paper towels down the toilet.
也许有人往马桶里扔了太多纸巾
I mean, we don't know what they are thinking, really, do we?
实在搞不清他们究竟在想什么 对不对?
No. What happened to you?
不 你是怎么了?
Nothing.
没什么
Nothing happened to me. I'm the same old Gary.
什么都没发生 我还是以前那个加里
- No shit.  - Huh!
- 扯淡  - 哼!
So, do you wanna?
那么 想来一炮吗?
- Oliver. I'll see you later.  - You're going?
- 奥利弗 待会见  - 你要走了?
I thought you weren't meeting The Twins for another half hour?
我以为你半小时后才去接双胞胎呢?
I'm not. Oh, yeah. I believe this is yours.
我改主意了 对了 这玩意应该是你的
"Out of order." It's a private joke.
"故障" 私人玩笑
I don't want to know.
我不想听
- What is that?  - Modern art.
- 那是什么?  - 现代艺术
It's a memorial, isn't it?
纪念碑吧 对吗?
Yeah. To modern art.
没错 纪念现代艺术
Hey. guys, do you know what time it is?
嘿 伙计们 现在是什么时间?
It's not even 6:00.
还不到六点
Wrong! it's high time we got onto The Cock!
答错了! 是我们冲进大公鸡的时间!
Whoo-hoo!
哇哦!
Let's go.
冲啊
Come on.
走吧
When you're ready, mate.
伙计 等你忙完了
Oh, shit. Look who it is.
天啊 瞧瞧那是谁
Basil. Mad Basil!
巴希尔 疯巴希尔!
Do you remember? We used to come in here
你们还记得吗? 我们以前老来这
and listen to him talk about fucking UFOs and lizard people and underwater Nazis.
听他讲关于飞碟 蜥蜴人 还有水底纳粹的鬼话
Didn't he spout some bullshit about the Bermuda Triangle
他是不是还说过百慕大三角
actually being a square?
实际上是方形的?
No, he said it was two isosceles triangles forming a rhombus.
不 他说那其实是个两个个等腰三角形拼成的菱形
He was your best mate, wasn't he, Steve?
他是你的好基友 对吗 史蒂文?
No, he wasn't my best mate, Gary.
不 他不是我的好基友 加里
He was a lonely, old guy and I felt a bit sorry for him.
他老无所依 我有点同情他而已
That's right. Basil!
没错 巴希尔!
Maybe we're not the local legends you think we are.
也许我们在这没你想的那么有名
- Gary King?  - Speak for yourself, mate.
- 加里・金?  - 说给你自己听吧
You're barred.
你被拉黑了
I cannot fucking believe this. This is ridiculous.
开什么玩笑 太可笑了
Believe me, Gary, it's not worth it.
相信我 加里 没必要啊
- Have two in the next one.  - Have them all in the next one, for all I care.
- 下场双倍啦  - 要我说 下场喝透算了
We've got to have one in every pub otherwise the whole thing's fucked.
每家酒馆都要喝一杯 否则就不算数了
I'd say it was fairly fucked already, mate.
伙计 我早就觉得没戏了
Great.
好极了
How much more of this do we have to endure?
我们还要忍受多久啊?
- That was three. There's nine more.  - Oh, good.
- 才逛了三家 还剩九家  - 哦 好极了
Fuck that. I need to eat something.
我操 我要吃点东西
We can get some food in the next pub.
下家店 我们去弄点吃的吧
As long as it's reasonably healthy.
只要那些东西吃起来健康就行了
This is Newton Haven.
这里是纽顿海文
Hardly the heart of the organic revolution.
估计跟有机和健康不沾边吧
I doubt it's the heart of anything.
我怀疑这里没什么跟现代搭边的
My wife wanted us to go organic, problem is, I kinda like eating shit.
我老婆想让我吃有机食品 问题在于 我更加偏向吃垃圾食品
The next pub does shit! Keep up!
下个酒吧专卖垃圾食品! 速度来!
Oh, yeah. I remember this one.
哦 赞啊 我记得这家店
- We had New Year's in here, didn't we?  - '89 into '90.
- 跨年狂欢 不是吗?  - 90年的新年那次
Isn't that when you slept on the pool table, Andy?
你是不是还在台球桌上睡着了 安迪?
Yeah. I believe it was.
没错 我还记得呢
- For six hours.  - Six hours.
- 足足睡了六个小时  - 六个小时啊
Thank you for reminding me.
多亏你提醒我啊
Do you remember when you woke up,
你还记得 你醒来的时候
we said you'd been asleep for a year and that it was 1991
我们骗你说 你睡了一年 现在是1991年
and you freaked out and punched a clock?
然后你被吓疯了 还把钟给打坏了?
That was a great night.
那晚上真是赞啊
Didn't you manage to get off with Erika Leekes, Peter?
你最后把艾瑞卡・里奇斯钓走了吗 皮特?
Yes, I did. Something of a personal triumph, if I say so myself.
妥妥的搞定 我必须说 完全是人生的丰碑啊
- She of the Marmalade Sandwich fame?  - Marmalade Sandwich...
- 她是那个甜心三明治的那个?  - 甜心三明治...
The very same.
真像啊
Two blondes and a redhead in the middle.
两个金发妞 夹着一个红发小魔女
- The Marmalade Sandwich.  - Becky Salt. Fucking hell.
- 甜心三明治  - 贝奇・索特 那身材啊
Wonder what they're doing now.
不知道她们现在在做什么?
Why don't you ask them?
干嘛不直接问她们呢?
What do you mean?
什么意思?
I mean, sitting at that table over there are two blondes and a redhead in the middle.
我说 那边卡间里 两边金发 中间红发
Shut the fuck up.
真他妈见鬼
I'd say that's Erika Leekes on the left, Tracy Benson on the right,
我猜左边是艾瑞卡・里奇斯 右边是崔西・本森
and by process of elimination, there's Becky Salt in the middle.
剩下的 中间肯定是贝奇・索特
That's the Marmalade Sandwich all growed up.
甜心三明治都成熟了啊
That is very spooky.
感觉好怪啊
- We should get them over.  - No.
- 我们把她们叫过来啦  - 别啊
Leave the past where it is.
不要破坏了过去的美好啊
It's bad enough having to look at your old, ugly mugs.
看着你这张皱巴巴的臭脸就很扫兴了
You make it sound like we're fucking ancient.
你这话说的 好像我们快入土的感觉
We haven't changed that much.
我们才没有变多少呢
- I mean, sure, Steve's let himself go a bit.  - What?
- 当然啦 史蒂文身材是走样了一点  - 什么?
Pete's got the same haircut and Oliver has still got his mark of the devil.
皮特的发型还是那么挫 奥利弗那鬼记号还在
- No, he hasn't.  - No, he hasn't.
- 奇怪 记号不见了  - 的确不见了
It's called laser surgery, Gary.
有个东西叫做激光手术 加里
It's a small price to pay for not being called fucking O-Man.
为了不被叫圈仔 这代价完全忽略不计
That works for Sisters of Mercy tattoos as well.
这手术也能除纹身 比如你身上的仁慈姐妹
I still like the Sisters Of Mercy.
我可喜欢这纹身了
Well, good job, or you'd never go swimming.
那好的吧 你就别想游泳了
- I'm lost.  - Don't be.
- 我不懂你说什么  - 少装傻
Well, I for one, think it's nice to see the old faces again.
我代表我自己 很高兴再看到你们这群老家伙啊
Cheers, mate.
多谢啦 伙计
Excuse me? This taken?
不好意思? 这位置有人坐吗?
Is this seat taken?
这位置有人坐吗?
Have it, mate.
拿去吧 伙计
Thanks.
谢啦
Wasn't that... Shane Hawkins.
那不是... 尚恩・霍金
- Hey, didn't he...  - Yes, he did.
- 话说 他不是...  - 没错 是的
Hang on. What happened with Shane Hawkins again?
等等 尚恩・霍金又怎么了?
I'd rather not bring it all up again, if that's okay.
没事的话 我还是不说的好
Hey, man. Listen, Pete.
伙计 皮特 听着
Bottling up past trauma can lead to
把童年的阴影深埋在心里
inadequate coping strategies in later life, apparently
会对未来的生活造成很大的影响 真的
I don't know, I mean, it's not even about the past, you know.
我也不知道 倒不是为了过去的事情
It's not about the fact that he bullied me,
不是因为上学他欺负我
that he made me miss more school days than chicken pox.
他害我请假比出水痘请假还多
It's not even that he forced me to spend entire lessons hiding in a toilet cubicle,
也不是因为他强迫我整节课躲在厕所蹲坑间里
or that he punched me so hard he dislodged my eyeball.
也不是因为他打我打到我眼球移位
And it's not even that he ruined a large portion of my childhood.
也不是因为他毁了我的童年生活
No, it's the fact that just then, he didn't recognize me.
都不是 只是因为就刚刚 他竟然认不出我了
He looked straight through me like it all meant nothing.
他直直地看着我 就好像之前他完全没这么对我过一样
That probably sounds weird, doesn't it?
这听起来很奇怪 是吧?
Shots!
干了!
S-H-O-T-S. Shots.
大 家 干 了 干杯
What are you doing, Gary?
你在干什么 加里?
I thought it was obvious. Shots.
我以为这很明显啊 喝酒啊
Firstly, Peter was talking about something
首先 皮特刚刚在说的事情
which clearly made him feel very uncomfortable.
很明显让他觉得很不开心的
- It's all right, Andy.  - No, Peter, it's not all right.
- 没事 安迪  - 错了 皮特 怎么可能没事
Secondly, 12 pints is more than enough, and thirdly, I don't fucking drink!
其次 十二杯酒完全超量了 最后 我戒酒了啊!
But shots don't count, do they?
但烈酒不算的 对吧?
You said you wanted to catch up and chew the fat.
你说 你想跟我们聊天叙旧 放松放松
I think you just wanted to drink it.
我觉得你就是想喝酒
We're not here as your friends.
我们连你的朋友都不是
We're just your fucking enablers.
我们变成你的酒友了啊
Enablers. That's a funny word, isn't it? Enabler.
酒友 这词好喜感 不是吗? 酒友
Gary King And The Enablers.
加里・金及他的酒友们
That's a good name for a band, Steve. Write that down.
这个做乐队的名字正好 史蒂文 记得记下来啊
Don't do a Gary, Gary.
别跟加里一样 加里
- Oh, is that a thing now, is it?  - It's always been a thing.
- 哦 现在还有这说法了 啊?  - 这说法一直都有
You don't need us to help you get fucked up,
你完全不用我们来灌你
you've done a perfectly good job so far on your own.
你自己一个人妥妥的可以把自己灌死
I'm gonna go and see if there's a bus back to London
我要去查查有没有回伦敦的公车
if anyone wants to come with me.
有人要跟我一起回去吗
You can't go. This is special. This is our anniversary.
你不能走 这次很特别的 这可是我们的纪念日
It's not the anniversary, Gary.
这不是什么纪念日 加里
We did this in June. It's October.
上次我们是六月 现在十月了
Yeah, but it's the anniversary of the year, isn't it?
没错 但今年是纪念日那年 对吧?
Every year is the anniversary of a year!
每年都是纪念日的一年
It's just not the same anymore, Gary,
如今不同往日了 加里
and it's not that the town's changed, we have changed.
不是这镇子变了 是我们变了
Yeah, well, you can't go, 'cause the buses are finished.
好吧 但你也走不了了 因为公车最后一班刚刚开走
Then I'm gonna go back to the B&B. You coming?
那我回家居旅馆了 你来吗?
I could do with an early one actually.
早点睡对我来说也不错的
I should probably go and find Sam.
我应该去出发找山姆了
Yeah, I'm gonna go and find Sam with Oliver.
是吧 我跟奥利弗一起去找山姆
That's settled then, yeah?
那就这么定了 行吗?
You know what I think? I think you're jealous.
你们知道我怎么想吗? 我觉得你们是在嫉妒我
Yeah, you've got your houses and your cars and your wives and your job security.
没错 你们是有房有车有老婆有工作
But you don't have what I have. Freedom.
但你们没有我的有的东西 自由
You're all slaves and I'm free to do what I want any old time.
你们是生活的奴隶 而我是自己的主人 跟以前一样
And this is what you want?
这就是你想要的吗?
You should grow up, mate. Join society.
你好快点长大了 伙计 闯荡一下社会
Yeah, but Mum died.
是啊 但我妈妈刚去世
And we're all very sorry, but now it's time to go home.
我们都恨遗憾 但现在是时候回家了
I thought we were home.
我以为我们已经回家了
I can't help feeling sorry for him.
我都为他感到遗憾啊
Don't.
混账
Oh! Fuck! Piss! Fuck...
哦! 操! 尿! 我操...
Careful, the floors a bit pissy.
当心 有人尿在地板上了
Wasn't me.
不是我干的
That was me.
那砖倒是我干的
Did that back in '90.
90年的时候干的
1990.
1990年的战绩
Punched the shit out of the wall.
把这墙打的一个洞啊
I don't know why. Seemed important at the time.
我不知道为什么 但那时候感觉很爽
You guys look like you're having a good night, though.
你们看上去玩得很开心的样子
I'm doing The Golden Mile tonight. You want to tag along?
我们正在进行豪饮马拉松 你要不一起来啊?
We'll be like The Six Musketeers.
我们可以组成六个火枪手的
I said we're doing The Golden Mile.
我说我们正在进行豪饮马拉松
You think you're so cool, don't you?
你用不用这么酷啊 啊?
Huh?
啊?
But we were cooler.
但我们更酷
We owned this town.
我们罩着这镇子的
We paved the way for you lot. Blazed a trail.
我们给你们铺了路 留了线索
Hey! Look at me when I'm talking to you!
嘿! 跟你说话呢 看着我!
- Please don't.  - Don't what?
- 请别这样  - 别这么样?
You don't want to do that.
最好别这么做
Don't I?
是吗?
What?
什么?
You need to explain this right now!
你现在给我好好解释一下!
Andy, this kid just attacked me.
安迪 这小子刚刚打我了
Don't you dare change the subject!
你少给我转移话题!
He smashed my head in the mirror.
他按着我的头撞玻璃
You know who I just spoke to? Your mum!
你知道我刚刚跟谁通话了吗? 你妈!
And not from the afterlife. From fucking Bournemouth.
不是地狱打来的 是从博纳矛斯
Is that real?
是真的吗?
She says she hasn't spoken to you for eight months.
她说 她已经八个月没跟你说过话了
- Andy...  - His head just came off!
- 安迪...  - 他的头就这么掉下来了!
No, Gary, you are not gonna wriggle out of it this time.
想都别想 加里 你这次不可能糊弄过关了
WTF
见他妈鬼
There's someone in here.
这坑有人占了
Andy, did you see...
安迪 你看到...
WTF, Gary. WTF.
见鬼 加里 什么情况
What the fuck does "WTF" mean?
什么情况是什么意思啊?
- What the fuck?  - Oh, yeah.
- 什么意思的意思  - 哦 懂了
This can't be happening. Can it?
这是开玩笑的吧 是吧?
You said it, mate.
你说呢 伙计
I can't believe it.
难以置信啊
I know, mate.
懂的 伙计
I can't believe you lied about your mum!
我不敢相信 你骗我们你妈妈的事情!
That was a white lie!
那无伤大雅!
- How is that a white lie?  - She's not dead, is she?
- 怎么无伤大雅啊?  - 她不是没死吗 不是吗?
Wait, wait, wait! Where are you going?
等等 等等! 你去哪里?
- To get help.  - No, don't do that!
- 去找帮手啊  - 别 先别声张!
- What, don't get help?  - We don't know how far this goes.
- 什么 别去找帮手?  - 我们还不知道是什么情况呢
- Wait, who are you calling?  - Vanessa.
- 等等 你打给谁呢?  - 维尼萨
- Who's Vanessa?  - My wife.
- 谁是维尼萨?  - 我老婆
- Why are you calling your wife?  - Because she's my wife.
- 为什么你要打给你老婆?  - 因为她是我老婆
You just said we don't know how far this goes.
你刚刚说 我们不知道是什么情况
- I was just thinking about the pub.  - Oh, well, there's a surprise.
- 我只是想说酒吧的事情  - 哦 你觉得是酒吧活动啊
I can't get through.
我打不通
Can you get through to Sam?
你能打通山姆吗?
I've got full bars and I'm not getting through.
我信号满格 但我也打不通
I'm sorry, your call cannot be connected at this time.
不好意思 您的电话现在无法接通
Must be the network.
肯定是网络的问题
Holy shit. This is all connected.
该死的 这一切都是有联系的
This explains why everything's gone fuck up.
这就解释了 为什么所有事情都变样了
Everybody's been replaced by one of these.
因为每个人都被这种东西调包了
That's why no one recognized us, Basil, Dave, Raymondo.
所以他们都不认识我们 比如巴希尔 戴维 雷蒙多
- I thought it was weird.  - Shane Hawkins.
- 我早就觉得奇怪了  - 还有尚恩・霍金
Exactly. it's not us that's changed, it's the town.
对的 不是我们变了 是这镇子变了
I'm right, aren't I, Andy?
我没说错 对吧 安迪?
- Andy, aren't I right?  - You're never wrong.
- 安迪 我说的对吧?  - 你从来没错过
No, whatever the fuck's happening, we can't stay in the gents forever.
的确 不管发生了什么 我们不能总躲在厕所里
Ten people have entered this toilet in the last five minutes
过去五分钟里 这厕所进了十个人
and not a single one has come back out again.
还没有一个人出这厕所门
That's going to look suspicious.
这情况很容易让人怀疑的
Gay loving.
搞基
And that's worse than five dismembered bodies.
这比五具残尸还糟糕
This is Newton Haven.
这里可是纽顿海文
- How's it looking?  - Normal. Very normal.
- 看上去怎么样?  - 正常 很正常
I don't like it.
我不喜欢这气氛
- What do we do?  - Let's finish our drinks.
- 我们怎么办?  - 先把酒喝了呗
I say we neck these and get the fuck out of here.
要我说 我们一口干 然后速度的离开这里
- To London?  - To The Trusty Servant.
- 去伦敦?  - 去忠仆
- Are you fucking kidding?  - Oh, yeah.
- 你搞笑吧?  - 哦 我错了
It's The Good Companions next. I always mix those two up.
下场是去好伙伴 我总是把这两个搞混
Are you saying we move on to the next pub?
你提议我们去下个酒吧?
We should get in The Beast and head back to London!
我们应该开上野兽 然后直奔伦敦
- My brake light is broken.  - So don't use the brakes!
- 我刹车灯坏了  - 那就别刹车啊!
- I'm way over the limit.  - When has that ever stopped you?
- 我早就醉酒了  - 你之前醉酒不也照开的吗?
I don't want to put any more points on Pete's license.
我不想再让皮特的驾照扣分了
Andy can drive, he's teetotal!
安迪能开 他滴酒未沾!
Ah!
啊!
That's settles it then.
那就这么定了
The last thing we need to do is get pulled over by the police.
我们最不希望的 就是被警察拦住
A, we're all drunk,
首先 我们都喝酒了
B, they might be in on it and, C, we've got blood on our hands.
其次 他们可能被调包 最后 我们手上都是血
- It's more like ink.  - We've got ink on our hands.
- 更像是墨水  - 我们手上都是墨水
- So, has it got messy yet?  - What?
- 那么 看起来还没造成什么乱子嘛?  - 什么?
- What are you, five pubs in?  - Four.
- 怎么样 逛了五家了?  - 才四家
Oh, not even halfway. Plenty more fun to be had.
哦 还没过一半啊 接下去乐子好多着呢
Enjoy your night, Peter.
玩的开心啊 皮特
Thank you.
多谢
谢谢
Sorry.
不好意思
The way I see it, we've told everybody we were doing The Golden Mile.
我觉得 我们跟所有人都说过了我们在豪饮马拉松
You did.
只有你说了
If we suddenly jump in The Beast now and head for the hills,
如果我们突然跳上野兽 回头走人的话
they're gonna know that we know,
他们就知道 我们知道了
but if we keep doing what we're doing and going where we're going,
但是如果我们继续按照预定计划的话
then they're not gonna know.
他们就不会知道了
- Know what?  - That we know.
- 知道什么?  - 我们知道的事情
I suggest we finish what we started and leave quietly in the morning.
我建议 我们把事情办完 然后明早安静地离开
- Wait. You're really suggesting...  - We finish The Golden Mile.
- 等等 那你是建议...  - 我们继续完成豪饮马拉松
It's pointless arguing with him.
跟他说就是对牛弹琴
Drink up. Let's Boo-Boo.
干了这杯 我们走人
We're just five friends
我们只是五个朋友
on a night out, having a good time.
晚上出来逛逛 找些乐子
- Drinking.  - Ah!
- 喝酒  - 啊!
- Beer.  - Pubs.
- 啤酒  - 酒吧
Shall we?
下一家?
I feel a little uncomfortable drinking this much.
喝这么多 我觉得有点不舒服
It's like Dutch courage, isn't it?
酒壮怂人胆 不是吗?
You know, when the English soldiers used to drink Dutch gin before battle
以前英国士兵经常杀敌之前喝荷兰的金酒
to give them super strength.
这会给他们非凡的勇气
You know, I thought that was to numb the sense of impending doom.
我觉得 那是为了削弱害怕的负面影响
Exactly.
完全正确
We're just five friends on a night out, having a good time.
我们就是五个好朋友 晚上出来逛逛 找些乐子
I need the toilet.
我要去厕所
- Go on then. You've earned it.  - Huh?
- 去吧 应该的  - 啊?
You're doing really good, Oliver.
你进步很多啊 奥利弗
He didn't make it this far last time. I'm proud of him.
上次他可没这么持久 我为他骄傲
You're enjoying this, aren't you?
你很享受现在 是吗?
Yeah, five guys on a night out, having a great time.
是啊 五个伙计大晚上一起出来 找乐子
Pretending to have a great time.
假装在找乐子
Are you pretending?
你是在装吗?
If we get out of here alive, I'm going to kill you.
如果我们活着出去 我就把你干掉
We're still in the dark, Gary.
别人还蒙在鼓里呢 加里
Yeah, our families could be in danger for all we know.
是啊 我们的家人可能都受到威胁了
I know, my mum could be dead. For reals this time.
我知道 我老妈这次可能真的要死了
- Hey, why don't we just ask somebody?  - Who?
- 嘿 为什么我们不问问其他人呢?  - 问谁啊?
- The Reverend Green. Come on.  - Wait.
- 就问绿圣人 跟上  - 等等
What the fuck are you doing?
你要去干嘛?
I'm going to go and have a little chat with The Reverend Green.
我过去跟绿圣人私下聊聊
You're going to buy drugs?
你是要去买毒品吗?
I am going to go over there and subtly check if that is The Reverend Green
我就过去旁敲侧击地打探一下他是不是绿圣人
and if it is, I can ask him what's going on,
如果是的话 我就能问他怎么回事了
and possibly buy some drugs.
也许顺便买点毒品
But what if he's one of them?
但如果他也是其中一员吗?
No, me and The Reverend had a highly sophisticated code
不可能 我和圣人谈起买大麻的时候
when discussing the purchase of herbal narcotics.
有个很复杂的暗号
If he doesn't understand me, it means he's one of them and I will simply walk away.
如果他不懂的话 那就说明他是其中一员 那我就走开好了
Ah!
啊!
- Have you got any drugs?  - I don't do that anymore, Gary.
- 还有大麻吗?  - 早就不干了 加里
- Do what?  - That.
- 做什么?  - 这暗号
That why you're in a suit, is it?
所以你穿西装打领带了 是吗?
'Cause drug dealing is not good enough for you?
因为贩毒不能满足你了吗?
There are no drug dealers anymore, Gary.
这里没人贩毒了 加里
I've got a proper job in a proper office.
我现在在固定地点 上固定的班
- You had a proper office.  - That was the gents' toilets.
- 你还有固定地点上班  - 那可是男洗手间
Nothing wrong with doing your business in the toilet.
你以前本来就在洗手间干营生
- Look, a lot has changed since you have left.  - I know.
- 听着 你走了之后 很多事情都改变了  - 我知道
- How much do you?  - A little.
- 你知道多少?  - 就一点
How much is a little?
一点是多少?
The town has been taken over by robots full of blue stuff.
镇子被一群蓝墨水机器人给占领了
Shh. Keep your voice down.
嘘 小声点
You don't even know what you're talking about.
你知道自己在说什么吗
- Tell us then.  - Well, they're not robots.
- 那告诉我们  - 他们不是机器人
Do you even know what robot means?
你知道机器人是什么吗?
Course I do. It's like, "Hello, I am a robot."
我当然知道啦 像这样"你好 我是个机器人"
It means slave and believe me, they are not slaves.
是奴隶的意思 而且相信我 他们不是什么奴隶
- Are you their prisoner?  - No, I am very happy.
- 你变成他们的囚犯了?  - 没有 我很开心
Tell your face.
说谎注意表情啊
Hey! What's going on?
嘿! 怎么样了?
The town's been invaded by robots who aren't robots
这个小镇被自称不是机器人的机器人占领了
- and The Rev's their prisoner.  - I am not.
- 他是他们的囚犯  - 我不是
We're leaving first thing. We can get you out of here.
我们马上就走了 我们能帮你逃出去
I'm not going. It's not what you think. This is for all our benefit.
我不会走的 这里也不是你们想的那样 这对我们大家都好
- You've said too much, Trevor.  - Yeah, put a cork in it, Trevor.
- 你说太多了 特拉沃尔  - 对 该停了 特拉沃尔
- I'm just trying to help.  - It's not your place to help.
- 我只是想帮忙  - 这里不该由你来帮忙
They will have everything in hand.
他们最后会知道一切的
Are you guys robots?
你们是机器人吗?
Well, the word robot actually comes from an old Czech word...
机器人这个词实际上起源于一个古老的捷克词语...
- robotnik...  - meaning slave.
- 机器...  - 意思是奴隶
- And we are not slaves.  - We are very, very happy.
- 我们不是奴隶  - 我们过得非常非常开心
And not robots.
所以我们不是机器人
Oh, my God, are these guys robots?
天啊 这些人是机器人吗?
Shut up about robots!
别再谈机器人了!
I say we shut up about everything!
我说我们什么都别再谈了!
Trevor.
特拉沃尔
It's your supervisor.
是你的监督人
- Hello, Trevor.  - Hello, sir.
- 你好 特拉沃尔  - 你好 先生
But...
但...
I understand.
我明白
Thanks a bunch.
太感谢你们了
What did I miss?
我错过了什么?
Your friends trying to help.
你的朋友们想帮忙
We don't need your help.
我们不需要你们的帮忙
Well, what should we do?
那我们该做什么?
I suggest you get on your way.
我建议你们该干什么就干什么
I think we should do what he says.
我觉得我们应该听他的
Okay.
好吧
双头狗
Here we go.
我们走吧
- Come on!  - Gary.
- 来吧!  - 加里
Gary!
加里!
Let's just get in and out of this one, yeah?
我们进去就马上出来 怎样?
No more making new friends.
不要再交新朋友了
Gentlemen! The prodigal sons return!
先生们! 浪子回归了!
What will it be, one of our guest ales perchance?
要点什么呢 不如来点啤酒?
Might I recommend five pints of Crowning Glory?
我推荐来五杯至高荣耀啤酒 如何?
- Rather fitting, wouldn't you say, Gary?  - What? Sorry. What?
- 非常合适 你觉得呢 加里?  - 什么? 不好意思 你说什么?
It's a delightful brew. Hoppy, nutty, foamy,
精心酿造 口感跳脱 令人迷醉 泡沫丰富
Does it have a surprisingly fruity note that lingers on the tongue?
喝完是不是还会在舌尖留下水果的味道?
You're obviously a connoisseur.
您一看就是个行家
Then you'll already know that it's a rare treat
那您肯定知道能喝到这种啤酒很难得
for rogues, reverends, royalty and all good folks between.
仅供流氓 传教士 皇室成员和其他好人
Five of those, please.
那就来五杯
Welcome home, boys.
欢迎回家 孩子们
I don't remember him being that friendly.
我都不记得他会这么友好
He's obviously one of them.
他显然是他们中的一员
How can he be? He remembered me.
他怎么可能? 他记得我
We don't know what they remember.
我们不知道他们记得什么
Maybe they have selective memories.
可能他们有选择性记忆
Yeah, like what's his name? Me.
没错 就像 他的名字是什么? 我
Maybe he's one of the others. Like The Reverend.
可能他是其他人中的一员 像老圣人
It is very hard to tell, isn't it?
这很难分辨 对吧?
Yeah, I mean, is he one of them or is he one of them?
对 我是说 他是他们中的一个还是他们中的一个?
Wait, wait, which ones are the thems again?
等等 等等 他们是哪个他们?
Well, they're both thems, aren't they?
有两个他们 对吧?
But there's two ways of saying it.
有两种方法来说
Is he one of them or is he one of them?
他是他们中的一个还是他们中的一个?
We need different terms.
我们要用不同的名称
One for the people who aren't robots and one for the robots who aren't robots.
一个指代不是机器人的人 还有一个指代自称不是机器人的机器人
All right, we need to be able to differentiate between them, them and us.
好吧 我们得能区分他们 他们和我们
Yeah, I think the pronouns are really confusing.
对 我觉得代词真的很难区分
Yes. I don't even know what a pronoun is.
对 我甚至都不知道代词是什么意思
It's a word that can function by itself as a noun
代词自身能起到名词的作用
which refers to something else in the discourse.
但在语境中指代其他东西
- I don't get it.  - You just used one.
- 我没听懂它  - 你刚刚就用了一个
- Did I?  - Yeah. "It" is a pronoun.
- 是吗?  - 用了 "它"就是个代词
- What is?  - It.
- 哪个词?  - 它
- Is it?  - Christ.
- 是它?  - 神啊
Look, we just need a fucking word so we can identify who's who.
听着 我们只是要找他妈的一个词而已 只要分辨谁是谁就行了
He's a blank, she's a blank, those two people are definitely blanks.
他是空壳 她是空壳 那两个人肯定也是空壳
Sam.
山姆
I got this, Steve.
我来 史蒂文
- All right, Sam?  - Oh, crumbs.
- 你好吗 山姆?  - 神经病
How's your night going?
今晚过得怎么样?
Good. Sort of.
挺好的 基本还不错
What do you mean "sort of"?
"基本"是什么意思?
Well, it's weird, isn't it?
真奇怪 不是吗?
You come back and everything's the same, but sort of different.
你回来后发现一切都没变 都又有点不同
Different how?
怎么不同了?
Just weird.
就是很奇怪
How weird?
怎么奇怪了?
What are you getting at, Gary?
你想知道什么 加里?
Come with me.
跟我来
残疾人洗手间
Puck's sake, Gary, take a hint.
去你妹的 加里 我没给你什么暗示
It's all right, I'm not trying to have sex with you.
没关系 我不是要和你做爱
Why are we in the disabled toilets then?
那我们为什么跑到残疾人洗手间里?
There's something I need to tell you right now,
现在我要告诉你一些事
unless you do want to have sex,
除非你确实想做爱
in which case I'll tell you afterwards.
那样的话 我们先做爱我再告诉你
Tell me right now.
现在就告诉我吧
Have you noticed anything creepy about The Twins
你有没有发现那对双胞胎有些惊悚的地方
apart from the fact that they're twins?
除了她们是双胞胎这个事实之外?
Just because they're twins doesn't automatically make them creepy.
她们是双胞胎不意味着她们很惊悚
- It does a little bit.  - You had sex with them.
- 不 确实会有点惊悚  - 你和她们上床了
A, I did not, and, B, how did you know about that?
第一 我没有 第二 你怎么知道的?
A, it's a small town, B, I'm not stupid and, C, they told me.
第一 这个镇子很小 第二 我不蠢 第三 她们告诉我的
Right. Well, I did once, but I was wasted,
好吧 我们确实睡过一次 但我快累死了
which was creepy because it was like there was four of them.
令人惊悚的就是那时好像有四个人在干我一样
I am not proud of it. I am a bit.
我一点都不骄傲 事实上我确实有点骄傲
- Is this what you wanted to tell me?  - No, this is...
- 这就是你想告诉我的?  - 不 这是...
- Are you okay, Sam?  - Are you okay, Sam?
- 你还好吗 山姆?  - 你还好吧 山姆?
I need a cigarette.
我想抽根烟
- Nobots?  - How about Fauxbots?
- 机器鬼?  - 机器假人怎么样?
I think we should get away from the whole robots thing.
我觉得我们应该彻底撇开这些机器人的问题
Steven?
史蒂文?
What's he up to?
他去干什么?
Oh, don't worry, he's probably just trying to fuck Oliver's sister.
别担心 他可能是想去上奥利弗的妹妹
Andy.
安迪
Oh, my God, that man is full of shit.
天啊 那个人就是个渣
I know that's not a surprise to you.
我知道这不会让你们惊讶
- What did he say, Sam?  - What did he say, Sam?
- 他说什么了 山姆?  - 他说什么了 山姆?
He said that Newton Haven has been taken over by robots full of blue stuff
他说牛顿海文被机器人占领了 机器人里都是蓝色的东西
and if we don't do what they say, they will make us their prisoners.
如果我们不按照他们说的做 他们就会把我们变成奴隶
- Did you believe him?  - Did you believe him?
- 你相信他吗?  - 你相信他吗?
No, of course not.
不信 当然不信
- Did you believe him?  - Did you believe him?
- 你相信他吗?  - 你相信他吗?
What?
什么?
- See?  - Come on, Sam.
- 看到了吗?  - 别信他 山姆
You know better than to believe Gary King,
你不会蠢到去相信加里・金的
Oh, crumbs.
神经病
Sam!
山姆!
God! You creepy bitches, get off!
天啊! 你们这两个疯婆娘 放手!
Chuck us a ciggie.
给我根烟
Oh.
哦
Gary, what's happening?
加里 发生了什么?
- I told you in the disableds.  - Oh, yes, you did.
- 我在残疾人厕所告诉过你了  - 哦 对 你说过
We should get inside, eh?
我们进去吧 嗯?
Otherwise people are going to ask what the hell's going on.
不然就会有人来问他妈的出什么事了
What the hell's going on?
他妈的出什么事了?
- Steve, I got this.  - Got what?
- 史蒂文 我发现了  - 发现什么了?
Sam, he's not good enough for you.
山姆 他配不上你
- What?  - What?
- 什么?  - 什么?
We've been through some crazy shit tonight
我们今晚经历了很多疯狂的事
and it's really put things in perspective for me,
这让我明白了一些事
and if everything is as fucked up as it seems, then there's something I need to tell you.
如果一切都像看上去那样神经 那么我要告诉你一些事
You might think this is because I've had seven pints, but it's not.
你可能会认为是因为我喝了七杯酒的关系 但不是的
It's not.
不是的
I'm in love with you, Sam.
我爱你 山姆
I always have been,
我一直都爱你
and it breaks my heart to see you waste your affections on Gary fucking King.
看到你把情感浪费在他妈的加里・金上 我很伤心
- Hey, that's a bit harsh.  - Oh, no, you've got it all wrong.
- 嘿 那么说有点难听  - 哦 不 你搞错了
- There's nothing between...  - And while I'm being honest,
- 没发生什么...  - 让我坦白告诉你
just to lay it all out there, I am currently seeing a fitness instructor.
把所有都摊开来说 我正在和一个健身教练谈恋爱
She's 26 years old,
她26岁
but I would drop her in a heartbeat if it meant
但如果我有一次机会能和你在一起
that I had one last chance with you.
我立马就会甩了她
Steven, there's nothing between me and Gary King.
史蒂文 我和加里・金之间没有什么事
Oh, fuck.
他妈的
Sorry.
不好意思
Hey! Get your feet off her!
嘿! 把你的脚从她身上拿开!
Pop its head off! Pop its head off like an aspirin bottle.
把头拧掉! 就像拧开阿司匹林药瓶一样把她的头拧掉
Blue-bloods?
蓝血人?
Nothing suggested in the last three minutes
过去3分钟我们的提议都不如
has been better than Smashy-Smashy Egg Men.
碎碎蛋头博士来得好
- No. Nothing.  - What the hell's going on?
- 都比不上  - 他妈的到底怎么回事?
Did you guys think of a name for the robots who aren't robots?
你们想好怎么叫那些自称不是机器人的机器人了吗?
I'm afraid we've drawn a blank.
我想我们就叫空壳人了
Well, we just had a barney with two blanks in the beer garden.
那我们刚刚就在花园里和两个空白人大干了一场
- We have to leave now!  - Agreed.
- 我们现在就走吧!  - 同意
Let's hit The Mermaid.
我们出发去美人鱼
- Wait, what?  - Number eight.
- 等等 什么?  - 第八家啊
"Number eight"?
"第八家"?
- Oh, fuck.  - Andy, what's happening?
- 他妈的  - 安迪 怎么回事?
Gary thinks we should keep on with the crawl because they know what we're doing
加里认为我们应该继续按计划行动 因为他们知道我们要做什么
but they don't know that we know what they're doing.
但他们不知道我们知道他们要做什么
And basically no one else has a better idea, so fuck it.
而且主要别人也没更好的主意 所以他妈的就这样了
What?
什么?
Wait!
等等!
Guys! Guys! I've got a better idea.
伙计们! 伙计们! 我有一个更好的主意
I'm parked right round here somewhere.
我的车就停在附近
Haul it. Just go! Steven, tell them!
把车开过来 我们就马上走! 史蒂文 告诉他们!
Gary said they'll get us if we try and leave now.
加里说如果我们现在打算离开 他们就会抓到我们
We're way past leaving now. Come on.
现在说离开已经太晚了 来吧
美人鱼
Oh, yeah.
没错 就该这样
This is what the kids want.
孩子们就想要这样的
This is a bit mad, isn't it?
有点疯狂 不是吗?
This is perfect. We can hide out in here. I'll get the drinks in.
这才是完美 我们可以躲在这里 我去拿点酒
- Good plan, O-Man.  - Hey!
- 好计划 圈仔  - 嘿!
Keep an eye out for blanks.
小心空壳人
You've got it.
你终于领会了
- Why didn't you say anything?  - About what?
- 你之前为什么不说?  - 说什么?
About what you said in the garden.
你在花园里说的那些
I always wanted to.
我一直想说
It just never seemed like the right moment.
但总觉得没有合适的时机
Something always got in the way.
总有别的事要做
Here you go, get these down you.
给 喝了这些吧
Thanks.
谢了
Steven?
史蒂文?
Please! I have so much to live for!
求求你! 我还有好多事没做呢!
- It's me, you numpty.  - Basil!
- 是我 你个笨蛋  - 巴希尔!
I knew seeing your faces again would spell trouble.
我就知道 看到你们的脸就意味着麻烦来了
Wait. How do I know it's really you?
等等 我怎么知道你是不是真正的你?
Because I'm the only one who's going to tell you the truth about Newton Haven.
因为我是唯一要告诉你牛顿海文真相的人
Now, do you recall the events of the evening of June the 22nd, 1990?
现在 你还记得1990年6月22号傍晚发生的事吗?
No, but I know a man who does.
不记得了 但我认识一个人 他记得
- Here you go.  - Hey.
- 给  - 嘿
See anyone we know?
有我们认识的人吗?
- The Marmalade Sandwich.  - The Marmalade Sandwich.
- 甜心三明治  - 甜心三明治
They look good.
她们还像过去一样美
- It's the lights.  - It's the drink.
- 是灯光的效果  - 是酒的效果
Who cares what it is?
谁管它是什么的效果?
Steven?
史蒂文?
That was the night they arrived.
他们就是那晚来的
Remember the shooting star? That was them.
记得那颗流星吗? 那就是他们
Nothing happened at first.
一开始什么事都没有
They were getting ready, burrowing in underground, preparing.
他们在准备 躲在地下 准备着
Not long after you lot left, people started to change.
不久以后 人们就开始转变了
Just one or two at first, then more.
一开始只有一两个 之后越来越多
They replaced people of influence, taking over the institutions,
他们替换了有影响力的大人物 占领了大学
remaking, remodeling, refurbishing.
重建 重塑 重组
Doing everything they could to make us join them.
他们尽一切可能 让我们成为他们
I can't find Steven. Where are the others?
我找不到史蒂文了 其他人在哪里?
They're blending in.
他们在调情
Oh, crumbs.
神经病
It's not like the replacements were evil, far from it.
替代品不是恶魔 完全不是
People got a lot friendlier. That's how they do it,
人们变得更友好 这就是他们做的
It's not an invasion, it's a merger.
这不是占领 是融合
They don't want to get rid of us, not if they can help it.
他们不想除掉我们 根本不想
They just want to make us more like them.
他们只是想让我们变得更像他们
Change the way we think.
改变我们思考的方式
Bring us into line with all the others.
把我们和其他人都带到一条生产线上
Become another link in their chain.
成为他们链条的一环
Which is fine, unless you say no.
这一切都很好 除非你拒绝
That's when you get replaced.
然后你就会被替换掉
Once they get your DNA, they've got you.
一旦他们拿到你的基因 你就完了
How do they do that?
他们怎么拿?
Any way they like.
用他们想用的任何方式
Blood tests, the nit nurse, sweat, kissing, saliva on the rim of a glass.
血液检测 打针护士 汗液 亲吻 杯缘的唾液
Why do you think I drink with this crazy straw?
不然我为什么要用这么奇怪的吸管喝酒?
Not so crazy now, is it?
现在看上去不那么奇怪了吧?
If you're not on their side, they'll create a version that is.
如果你反对他们 他们就会创造一个同意他们的你
They can bring you back exactly the same or even make you young again.
他们可以复制一模一样的你 甚至创造更年轻的你
It looks like you, it even has your memories,
那看上去很像你 甚至还有你的记忆
but really it's just a vessel to spread their message.
但事实上那只是传播他们信息的管道
Trust, love, respect, desire.
信任 爱 尊敬 欲望
Replaced in the name of progress.
都以进化的名义被取代了
So, what happens to the people who get replaced?
那么 那些被替代的人怎么样了?
The empties? Don't ask me what happens to them.
废容器? 别问我他们怎么样了
Why, what happens to the empties?
为什么 废容器怎么样了?
I told you not to ask me that!
我告诉过你不要问我!
Go! Get out, before it's too late!
快走! 快离开这里 否则就太晚了!
- Basil?  - I said go!
- 巴希尔?  - 我说过快走!
This just can't be good.
这太不好了
Sam, who was the boy that you liked in sixth form? Adrian?
山姆 你高二高三的时候喜欢的男孩子是谁? 阿德里安?
Adrian Keane. Why?
阿德里安・基恩 怎么了?
He's over there.
他在那里
Hey, Sam. How's life?
嘿 山姆 过得怎么样?
- Sam, we have to get out of here!  - We have to get out of here!
- 山姆 我们得离开这里!  - 我们得离开这里!
- Where are the others?  - They're blending in.
- 其他人在哪里?  - 他们在调情
Oh, fuck!
他妈的!
- Gary!  - Oh. No, just one more song.
- 加里!  - 不要 再来一首歌
Gary, she's a blank!
加里 她是空白人!
Don't be so judgmental.
别这么歧视
Oh, for fuck...
他妈的...
学校联谊会
Oh, yeah. Come on.
好吧 走吧
Still got it. Enough's enough.
还是到手了 够了就是够了
Let's go.
我们快走
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold up. Hold up.
哇 哇 哇 等等 等等
Where are you all going?
你们要去哪?
- We're leaving.  - Really? What happened?
- 我们要走了  - 真的? 怎么回事?
- Adrian Keane was in that bar.  - Prick.
- 阿德里安・基恩在酒吧里  - 蠢货
I thought you liked Adrian Keane.
我还以为你喜欢阿德里安・基恩
- Adrian Keane is dead.  - Oh, God.
- 阿德里安・基恩已经死了  - 天啊
Adrian Keane died in a motorbike accident in Italy eight years ago.
八年前在意大利 阿德里安・基恩死于一场摩托车事故
- Did he?  - They must have had his DNA on file.
- 是吗?  - 他们肯定拿到了他的基因
That's how they were able to replicate him.
然后才能复制一个他
They know how to get to us, man. They know everything.
他们知道怎么抓到我们 老兄 他们知道一切
- They didn't know Adrian was dead.  - They knew enough to tempt us.
- 他们不知道阿德里安死了  - 他们知道的足够诱惑我们了
They knew these three would fall for a bunch of girls in school uniform.
他们知道这三个家伙看到穿着校服的姑娘就无法自拔
- Hey, who wouldn't? Am I right?  - Fuck, yeah.
- 嘿 谁不会呢? 我说的对吧?  - 他妈的还真对
We've gotta get out of town,
我们得离开这个镇子
we've gotta get beyond it before it's too late.
我们得在事情恶化之前离开这里
- Where are you getting all this from?  - Basil.
- 谁告诉你这些的?  - 巴希尔
Mad Basil? He of the Bermuda Rhombus and the Aqua Nazis?
疯子巴希尔? 说百慕大四角洲和水下纳粹的?
Another good name for the band, Steve.
又一个很好的乐队名字 史蒂文
You're putting our lives in the hands of a crazy old man?
你就把我们的生命赌在那个疯老头身上?
- He's not crazy!  - No, maybe he's not.
- 他没有疯!  - 或许他没疯
Or maybe he's a blank trying to lure us to the edge of town,
或许他就是个空壳人 想引诱我们走到镇子边缘的
onto those dark country roads where they can deal with us.
黑色乡间小路上 然后他们就会把我们干掉
- Yeah, we could end up dead in a field.  - I hate fields.
- 没错 我们可能最后会死在稻田里  - 我讨厌稻田
Yes. My thoughts precisely.
没错 我也是这么想的
Steven's right. We should go.
史蒂文说的对 我们应该离开
No, we're going to The Beehive.
不 我们要去蜂巢
Gary's plan is still the best we have.
加里的计划仍然是现在的最佳计划
Wait a minute
等一下
The 1990-model Oliver was out of commission by this point in the evening.
九零款奥利弗在今晚此时退役
What are you saying?
你在说什么?
- I like the new you.  - Huh.
- 我喜欢新的你  - 哈
Come on.
走吧
This is a mistake, isn't it?
这样做是不对的
Hold up! Just stick with me.
快点! 跟我走
Andy, come on!
安迪 来啊!
Here we go. Pub number nine.
到啦 第九个酒吧
Fuck yes!
太他妈对了!
That's the spirit, Pete! Spirits! We should do chasers.
这就是目标 目标! 皮特! 追求目标吧
Who is this guy?
你真令人刮目相看
Come on. Andy! It can't start without you.
来吧 安迪! 少了你就没法开始了
You what?
你说什么?
We can't start without you.
我们没你可不行
Now then. Whose round is it?
好 现在轮到谁了?
It's mine.
我来
Mr. Shepherd! Is it Mr. Shepherd?
谢菲尔德先生! 是谢菲尔德老师?
Why don't you kids join me? You look like you could do with a drink.
你们几个小鬼来一起坐吧? 一起喝一杯
Now, let's have a little chat about your future, shall we, hmm?
来谈谈你们的未来 怎么样?
- Uh, Mr. Shepherd?  - Please, call me Guy.
- 谢菲尔德老师?  - 请叫我哥们
All right.
好吧
Guy...
哥们...
Look at you.
瞧瞧你
Are you a robot?
你是机器人吗?
Does anyone know what robot means?
谁知道机器人语出何处?
- Yeah. I do!  - Yes, Gary.
- 我知道!  - 请说 加里
It means "slave."
意思就是"奴隶"
Oh, very good, Gary.
很好 加里
Are you a robot, sir?
那你是机器人吗?
No, Peter, of course I'm not a robot.
不 皮特 我当然不是
- Sir?  - Yes, Steven.
- 先生?  - 请说 史蒂文
But you're on their side, though?
但你站在他们那边的 对吗?
This is not about sides, Steven.
无关站在哪边 史蒂文
It's not about shirts versus skins.
这与外在无关
It's about working together as one team.
这关乎精诚合作
I know it may seem a bit weird and a little bit scary,
我知道有点奇怪 还有点吓人
but please believe me, it's quite the opposite,
当请相信我 完全不是这样的
They're here to help.
他们是来帮助我们的
To straighten us out. To prepare us for the big league.
纠正我们 让我们准备好加入大家庭
They've seen something in us, a potential.
他们能看到我们的潜力
There's a vast community of worlds up there,
在那上面还有个庞大的社会
living together, peacefully, cooperatively.
一起生活 和平 合作
And guess what? They want us along for the ride.
知道吗? 他们想让我们加入
Pretty cool, eh, gang?
很不错吧 兄弟们?
So, they're not here to harm us?
那么 他们不会伤害我们?
Far from it, O-Man. No, they're here to help.
怎么会呢 圈仔 他们是来提供帮助的
I'm not saying they're afraid to get tough.
我可没说他们惧怕暴力
I certainly had to get tough with you in my day.
过去我可被你们折腾的够呛
And what one amongst you wouldn't thank me for it? Hmm?
难道你们中没有一个人对我表示感谢吗?
In some respects, they're a lot like teachers.
请表示尊敬 他们其实更像教师
Stern, yes. A little frightening.
严格 没错 有些可怕
But it's all for our betterment.
但都是为了我们好
So, what do you say we all go somewhere and talk about this properly?
我们要不要一起换个地方体面地谈谈这事儿?
That wasn't properly?
这么谈不体面吗?
Well, I think it's pretty clear, guys, what Mr. Shepherd is trying to say is that...
嗯 我看很显然 谢菲尔德老师是想告诉我们...
Andy! What the fuck?
安迪! 你干什么?
Yes, Andy. What the fuck?
是啊 安迪 你干什么?
Humans, you leave us no recourse.
人类 你们让我们别无选择
If you will not join us willingly,
如果你们不肯自愿加入我们
we will be forced to use other means of persuasion.
我们只能采取别的方式让你们就范
Now, please...
现在 请...
I fucking hate this town!
我他妈恨死这里啦!
Oh, oh!
哦 哦!
- Oh, crumbs, you're heavy.  - Sorry.
- 哦 哥们 你真重  - 不好意思
Motherfucker!
该死的!
Andy!
安迪!
Twist the melon, man!
强扭瓜 哥们!
Yeah!
棒!
Sam, this is no way for a family to behave.
山姆 你难道连家人都不信任了吗
Sam, I'm disappointed in you.
山姆 我对你很失望
O-Man!
圈仔!
Okay, Andy.
好了 安迪
Break it up.
扯碎它
It doesn't have to be like this.
完全没必要这样
It could be so much simpler, so completely painless.
其实可以很简单的 完全没有痛苦的
If only you'd see the light.
你们只需要看着那光
Yes.
是的
See, it's not about conflict,
完全无需挣扎
it's about togetherness.
只是聚合而已
Yes. Let's try this again, shall we?
好吧 再来一波 怎么样?
How about another round?
在来一轮吧?
Nah, we're done here.
不了 这的酒已经喝了
Yes, Gary, that appears to be the case.
好吧 加里 那试试这个
The Smokehouse!
烟屋!
- What?  - Just do it!
- 什么?  - 快走!
Come on!
快点!
This way!
这边!
Humans, this is your final warning.
人类 这是最后通牒
Failure to comply will result in your...
若仍不服从 会导致...
Humans, obey now, or face the consequences.
人类 立即服从 否则将承担一切后果
Let's go!
快走!
Shit.
该死
Oh, look, there's my car!
哦 看 那是我的车!
Let's climb down the drainpipe.
顺着排水管下去
I've got a better idea.
我有更好的办法
Climb down the drainpipe.
还是爬水管吧
Okay, just go.
好了 快走
Wait. What about the others?
等等 他们呢?
Leave 'em with me, okay? I got this.
有我呢 交给我了
- Are you sure?  - Yeah, I always land on my feet.
- 你行吗?  - 当然 我绝对靠得住
I don't know if that's true, Gary.
让我很难相信 加里
Just go.
快走
Will you find out what happened to my brother?
别忘了找到我哥哥
Yeah, of course, of course, and I'll look after Stevie for you, eh?
当然 放心好了 我还会照顾好史蒂文的
He's a good guy. He's better than me.
他是个好男人 比我强
Gary, you're not a bad person, but you're not boyfriend material.
加里 你不是坏人 不过你不是当男朋友的料
The whole "free spirit quick one in the disabled toilets" thing
"在残障厕所里快速来一发自由精神"这种事情
is kinda cool when you're 17, but not when you're facing 40.
十七岁玩还可以 但是你现在已经奔四了
There comes a time when you have to go forwards and not backwards.
你得成熟起来 不能再幼稚了
Maybe if I hadn't left you behind that night, things would all be different.
如果我那晚没有甩了你 现在事情就大不一样了
It's not all about that night, Gary.
不仅仅是那晚的事 加里
Isn't it?
是吗?
It doesn't have to be.
根本就不该开始
We'll always have the disableds, though, won't we?
事情总是不能令人满意 是吧?
Yeah. Yeah, we'll always have the disableds.
没错 总是不能令人满意
Oh, no.
哦 不
Where's Sam?
山姆呢?
I put her in her car.
我把她送到车上了
You did what?
你怎么她了?
I put her in her car. I just told her to leave.
我把她送到她的车上了 我告诉她让她走
You just sent away the only one of us sober enough to drive?
你把唯一清醒能开车的人送走了?
- Yeah.  - You just couldn't stand the fact
- 对  - 你是没法接受
that she might prefer me to you.
她更喜欢我这个事实
- That's not true.  - It is true, Gary!
- 瞎扯  - 本来就是 加里!
I was getting somewhere. We held hands.
我和她关系不一般 手拉手来着
- I was just trying to help!  - You were trying to help yourself, more like!
- 我是想帮忙!  - 你在帮自己!
Jesus, I do something right for a change and you fuckers get on my case.
上帝啊 我将功补过来着 你们还没完了
Wow, that's the first time I've ever heard you admit being wrong.
哇 头次听到你承认错误
I said I did something right!
我说的是将功 功!
Yeah, "for a change".
对啊 "补过"不是吗
So? Meaning the rest of the time you're wrong.
所以 这说明你肯定做错了什么
Not necessarily.
不可能
Look, I just thought it was best to keep her out of harm's way.
听着 我是想让她离开这危险的地方
And what about us, Gary? Aren't we in harm's way?
那我们呢? 我们就呆在这危险的地方?
We're all right, Pete. Come on, we're The Five Musketeers.
我们没事的 皮特 开玩笑 我们可是五个火枪手
No, we're the Four Musketeers.
不 现在是四个火枪手了
Wait, how do we know you put her in the car?
等下 我们怎么知道你让她上车了?
How do we know you're you?
我们怎么知道你是你?
Of course I'm me!
我当然是我!
- Well, who the fuck are you, Gary?  - I'm Gary King.
- 你到底是谁 加里?  - 我是加里・金
There's only one Gary King. How do I know you guys are you?
只有一个加里・金 我怎么知道你们是谁?
We've been together the whole time.
我们一直在一起
You might all not be you. How did you know O-Man wasn't O-Man?
也许你们全被换了呢 你怎么知道圈仔不再是圈仔了?
Because his birthmark was back.
因为他的胎记回来了
- What does that prove?  - Because of what Basil said.
- 那怎么了?  - 巴希尔说过
They make a copy from your DNA.
他们通过基因复制人
That's why he had his birthmark.
所以他的胎记又出来了
He was new, like a baby.
他是新的 就像刚生下一样
Like a man-baby. Like a "maybe".
成人版婴儿 或者婴儿版成人
Oliver with none of the shit that had happened to the real Oliver.
假的奥利弗不会有真奥利弗身上那些后天的东西
The laser surgery!
激光除痕手术!
So the blanks really are just blank?
所以空壳真的是只是空壳?
No wear and tear, no scars.
没装饰 没眼泪 没伤疤
Steven, in 1987 we were playing cricket and I accidentally pushed you
史蒂文 1987年我们玩板球我推了你一把
onto a broken bottle that nearly went up your ass.
你坐在玻璃瓶上了差点爆了菊花
- So?  - Show us your bum.
- 干嘛?  - 让我们看你的屁股
- Very nice.  - Thank you.
- 很漂亮  - 谢谢
Pete, you got that 50cc Suzuki in 1988,
皮特 1988你搞到了一辆铃木摩托
and you let me have a go on it and I ran over your leg.
我骑的时候轧过了你的腿
What the fuck?
什么情况?
Oh, wait, it's the other one.
等等 是另一条腿
Andy, in 1986 we re-enacted the Knife Game from Aliens
安迪 1986年我们一起玩刀的时候
and I stabbed you in the middle finger.
我把你的中指扎穿了
How about December 1997, when you OD'd
怎么不提1997年 你嗑药过量
and I drove you to the hospital four times over the limit
我开车送你去医院 四倍超速
and I ended up rolling the car and almost severing my femoral artery,
车翻了 我差点弄断自己的股动脉
at which point you made a miraculous fucking recovery
然后你奇迹般的恢复正常
and ran off into the night, leaving me to get arrested
直接午夜狂奔了 留下我一个人
after 12 hours of life-saving surgery?
经过了十二小时抢救才活下来?
Either one of those will do.
你说这些没意义
- Thank you.  - What about you?
- 谢谢  - 你呢?
That's easy.
很简单
- That could have been drawn on.  - Aren't all tattoos drawn on?
- 那很容易就画上去的  - 纹身不都是画上去的吗?
- Yeah.  - Show us your arm.
- 没错  - 让我们看胳膊
- What?  - Show us your arm.
- 啥?  - 把胳膊露出来
No, no.
不 不
You fell off stage at the fifth-year ball fucking around and dislocated your elbow.
你在五年级舞会上从舞台上掉下来 胳膊肘脱臼了
You've got a scar where they put the metal plate in.
装入钢板的时候留下了疤
I don't have to show you anything, all right?
我没必要给你们看任何东西 好吧?
I'm Gary King. I know I'm me.
我是加里・金 我知道自己是
If I'm not me, then how do I know that carved into that beam above your head
如果我不是我 我怎么知道你头上那梁上
are the words "King Gary"?
刻着的字是"国王加里"?
But it doesn't say "King Gary".
那刻得根本不是什么"国王加里"
Yes, it does. Doesn't it?
怎么可能 绝对是!
No. It says "King Gay".
不 那刻着是"国王基佬"
Some cunt scrubbed out the "R"!
哪个混蛋把"R"给我划掉了!
- That was me.  - Why?
- 是我  - 为什么?
"King Gay". That means fuck-all anyway.
"国王基佬" 意思是后宫三千尽菊花
Mr. Shepherd remembered stuff, so did Oliver.
谢菲尔德老师都记得 还有奥利弗
Selective memory, remember?
选择性记忆 明白吗?
We don't see you for years and you just pitch up and bring us here.
我们多少年没见你了 一见面你就把我们骗来这里
You better come out with some hard evidence that you're human,
你还是想点有力的证据证明你是人类吧
otherwise we're going to find out for ourselves.
否则我们就动手证明了
You want evidence?
你想要证据?
There!
瞧着!
That proves I'm human!
这可以证明我是人类!
It proves you're stupid.
这可以证明你够蠢
Exactly!
说得对!
Ow!
噢!
It's Gary. It's Gary.
他是加里 是他
The whole town's out looking for us.
所有人都在找我们
That's a good thing. If everybody's outside, that means nobody's inside.
好事 所有人都在外面 那里面就没人了
Gary, wait! Fuck!
加里 等等! 该死!
Gary, Gary! What do you mean "nobody's inside"?
加里 加里! 什么叫"里面就没人了"
I mean we can still do this!
我是说我们可以继续!
Do what exactly?
继续什么?
Oh, we're still on the crawl.
继续行动啊
"King Gay".
"国王基佬"
Peter?
皮特?
Peter.
皮特
I thought that was you. Are you okay?
我就觉得是你 你没事吧?
Am I what?
我怎么?
I know we didn't see eye to eye at school.
我知道在学校我们互相看不顺眼
Goodness knows I regret that.
上帝作证我是想表示歉意
I wanted to say something back at the pub,
刚才在酒吧里我就想跟你说了
but I felt so terribly ashamed by what I'd done.
但我对自己做的事情觉得很羞耻
Let me make it up to you, Peter. Please.
接受我的歉意吧 皮特 求你了
Gary, you're out of your mind! We've come too far.
加里 你疯了吗? 我们跑太远了
It's fucking suicide.
这是要自杀
I know. We are going to get to The World's End if it kills us.
我知道 哪怕死了 我们也要到世界尽头去
Where's Pete?
皮特呢?
I hate you!
我恨你!
You fucking bastard! I hate you!
你这该死的的混蛋! 我恨你!
Pete! Leave it! Why are you doing this, Peter?
皮特! 别这样! 你这是干嘛啊 皮特?
We don't want to hurt you.
我们不想伤害你
Come on, mate! It's not worth it!
行了 哥们! 没必要这样!
Yes, it fucking is!
有必要 绝对有必要!
What's he doing?
他干什么?
Oh, shit.
该死
Peter...
皮特...
I must say, I'm very disappointed in you, Peter.
我得说 我对你很失望 皮特
I'll punch their fucking lights out.
我要把它们的灯都捶灭
Andy! No, no, no, there's too many of them.
安迪! 不行 它们数量太多
Pete.
皮特
Peter.
We gotta go. Gary's right.
我们得走了 加里说的对
We gotta get to The King's Head. Exactly.
我们要去国王之颅
What?
啥?
We are not going to The King's Head. We're done.
我们不去国王之颅 那事儿完了
We're going to do what we should have done in the first place.
我们要做早都该做的事情
Get The Beast and get out of here.
去开上野兽 立即离开这里
We are fucking leaving and we are never coming back.
立即他妈的离开 绝不再来
Now, you can either come with us willingly
你可以自愿跟我们走
or I'm gonna knock you the fuck out and carry you there myself.
或者我把你干到然后扛着你走
- You choose.  - All right. All right.
- 你选吧  - 好了好了
Just think about what you're saying, you know, because you have been drinking.
你知道自己在说什么吗 你喝多了
You fuck.
你混蛋
Shit, it's those fucking kids.
该死 是那群小孩
Not them again.
可别再来了
What the hell is that?
那到底是什么?
I don't know, but it's definitely not modern art.
不知道 反正绝不是什么现代艺术
Oh, shit, we're trapped. Where's The Beast?
该死 被围住了 野兽在哪?
Okay, all right. We're here, so The Beast is in the next street.
好 我们在这里 野兽停在下一条街
How are we gonna get to it?
怎么过去?
- We'll have to go through.  - Through where?
- 穿过这家店  - 哪家店?
I don't fucking believe this.
真他妈难以置信
Number 10.
第十个
Come on.
快点
Let's go.
快走
The backdoor, back door. Let's go.
后门 后门 快走
Here we go.
就这里
Okay, there it is.
就是这
Shit.
该死
We wait for an opening, and then we leg it to The Beast.
等空壳们没过来的时候 跑过去
We need the keys.
车钥匙呢
Gary?
加里?
Gary, what are you doing?
加里 你干什么呢?
Just a little toast.
喝一点而已
Gary, put the pint down, yeah?
加里 把酒杯放下 好吗?
To Oliver, Pete.
敬奥利弗 皮特
And to us.
还有我们
You know, 'cause 10 pubs isn't bad,
知道吗 十个酒吧已经不错了
It's not, but we're calling time.
是不错 没时间了
Okay.
好吧
So close.
就差一点了
Number 10.
第十个
Okay.
好吧
So close.
就差一点了
No, no, no, no, no. Gary!
不 不 不 不 加里!
Gary! Gary!
加里! 加里!
Let him go. He left you, man.
让他去吧 他以前也这么干过 哥们
I can't.
我不能
Andy!
安迪!
Gary! Gary!
加里! 加里!
Gary, come back! Come back, you stupid bastard!
加里 快回来! 回来你个蠢货!
Gary!
加里!
Gary! Gary!
加里! 加里!
Andy, look out!
安迪 小心!
Come on!
拜托!
What the...
你他妈...
Get in. Get in.
进来 进来
Gary, Andy, get the fuck in!
加里 安迪 快点进来!
You heard him, Andy. Get the fuck in.
你听到了 安迪 快进去
We haven't much time!
没时间啦!
- Andy! Go, now!  - Steven!
- 安迪! 快跑!  - 史蒂文!
Go!
快跑!
Andy.
安迪
I want you inside me.
来插我吧
Okay.
好吧
Cheers.
哟呵
Ah!
啊!
- You've had enough!  - This is The World's End, man!
- 你够了!  - 这里是世界尽头!
I know!
我知道!
Stop this!
别这样!
Leave me alone! What do you care anyway?
别管我! 干嘛管我啊?
Of course I fucking care. There's a reason I'm angry at you!
我当然要管你 我对你很生气!
I know why you're angry at me, okay?
我知道你为什么生我气
But it's not my fault that you crashed that car.
但你把车开翻了管我什么事
That's not the point. You let me down, man.
不是说这个 你让我失望了 哥们
You were Gary King. Gary fucking King.
你是加里・金 该死的加里・金
I would have followed you to the end. I fucking have!
我应该跟你走向世界尽头 我做到了!
Then stop following me!
那就别跟着我了!
No! It's just one more.
不! 再来一杯
Let me have this.
让我喝了这杯
You've got everything you want.
你们想要的都得到了
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢?
You've got your perfect job and your perfect house and your perfect wife.
你们有好工作 好房子 好老婆
You think it's so perfect?
你觉得这些很好吗?
She left me, Gary.
她走了 加里
She took the kids to her mum's three weeks ago,
她三周前带着孩子回娘家了
Said I'm not present enough. I'm trying to win her back.
说我不够好 我努力地想把她追回来
And God knows I am losing.
我才是个失败者
But I will continue to fight, because that is how we survive.
但我还不放弃 这就是我们的生存方式
For fuck's sake, Gary, I just punched my wedding ring out of a robot's tummy.
该死的 加里 我刚刚把我的结婚戒指从一个机器人的胃里掏出来了
Exactly! You fight for what's important.
说得对! 你为了重要的东西而奋斗
But what is so important about The Golden Mile?
豪饮马拉松对你来说这么重要吗?
It's all I've got!
我只有这个追求了!
Gary.
加里
查特汉姆皇家医院 精神科
You need help, Gary.
你需要帮助 加里
I got help. You know what help was?
我得到帮助了 你知道是什么样的帮助吗?
Help was a lot of people sitting in a circle
帮助就是一群人坐成一个圈
talking about how fucking awful things had got.
互相说着那些自己身上发生的可怕的事
That is not my idea of a good time.
那不是我想要的好日子
- And this is?  - They told me when to go to bed.
- 那这就是了?  - 他们告诉我该上床睡觉了
Me!
我!
Gary, mate, how can you tell when you're drunk if you're never sober?
加里 兄弟 从没清醒过你怎么能知道自己醉了?
I don't wanna be sober.
我不想清醒
It never got better than that night.
那一晚无与伦比
That was supposed to be the beginning of my life.
那本该是我开始新生活的一晚
All that promise and fucking optimism.
那样的承诺和乐观
That feeling like we could take on the whole universe.
感觉我们就像拥有整个宇宙
It was a big lie.
全是谎话
Nothing happened.
什么都没有发生
You don't need to do this, Gary.
你没必要这样 加里
Yeah, I do.
有 有必要
Please, stand by.
请勿移动
Ah!
啊!
What are you doing?
你干什么?
No, don't go out there.
别 别出去
Gary King.
加里・金
Yeah?
是我
Gary King of the humans.
人类成员加里・金
Yeah. What do you want?
是我 想干嘛?
We are here to enable your full potential,
我们是来激发你们全部潜能的
as we have with countless worlds across the galaxy.
就像在银河不可胜数的世界上做的一样
Oh, yeah? How'd you manage that, then?
是吗? 说说怎么做的?
We appropriate a small percentage of the population
我们在星球上2000个左右的渗入区
at 2,000 or so penetration points across the planet.
侵占一定比例的人口
This ensures maximum coverage.
用以保证一定的覆盖率
From there, we create simulants to spread our ideologies
从那里 我们制造复制人通过和平教化
through peaceful indoctrination.
来传播我们的观念
Our objective is simple, to ready the population
我们的目标很简单 让这里的居民做好准备
for participation in our galactic community.
加入我们的伟大社会
This method requires a small sacrifice.
这种方法需要一定的牺牲
But the fewer replacements we make,
但是我们对行动的评估
the more successful we consider our operation.
主要取决于替换人数的多少 越少越好
Of course, we welcome those who volunteer themselves.
当然 我们欢迎志愿者
We can offer attractive incentives for those who willingly combine.
对自愿合作的人 我们提供极好的奖励
The chance to be young again and yet retain selected memories.
可以返老还童 并选择性地保留记忆
Isn't that something you'd like?
这样你们不喜欢吗?
Something you've always wanted?
你们一直想要的东西?
Oh, my God! I'm so cute!
天呐! 我真帅!
The beauty of our system is that we all win.
这种双赢正是我们系统的美好之处
There are no losers.
没有失败者
Allow me to carry your legend forward.
让我续写你的传奇
Let the man you have become be the boy you were.
让年轻的自己重走你的人生路
Nah.
不要
There's only one Gary King.
只有一个加里・金
Then you have made your choice, Gary King of the humans.
这就是你的选择了 人类成员加里・金
Yeah, I have.
对 是我的选择
Because frankly, who the fuck are you to come down here and tell us what to do?
话说回来 你他妈是什么东西啊来这里指手画脚的?
We are The Network and we are here for your betterment.
我们是网络 我们来为你们谋福利
In the last 23 years,
在过去的二十三年中
have you not marveled as information technology has surged forward?
你难道没察觉到信息技术的爆炸式发展吗?
No.
没有
Earth has grown smaller yet greater as connectivity has grown.
随着沟通的增强地球本身变得小而精彩
This is our doing and it is just the beginning.
这是我们的杰作 这仅仅是个开始
Oh, fuck off, you big lamp.
哦 得了吧 大灯泡
You are children and you require guidance.
你们是孩子 你们需要教导
There is no room for imperfection.
不能容忍瑕疵的存在
Hey, Earth isn't perfect, all right? And humans aren't perfect.
地球本不完美 好吗? 人类本不完美
And guess what? I ain't perfect.
知道吗? 连我也不完美
And therein lies the necessity for this intervention.
因此才需要我们的介入
Must the galaxy be subjected to an entire planet of people like you?
难道银河要受制于你们这种人所管理的地球吗?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
哇 哇 等等
Who put you in charge, huh?
凭什么你说了算 啊?
Who are you to criticize anyone?
你有什么资格评判别人?
Now, you might think Gary's a bit of a cock,
你也许觉得加里是个混球
and he is a bit of a cock, but he's my cock.
虽然他确实有点混 但我喜欢
Oh, thanks, man.
谢谢 哥们
But he is a detriment to himself, just as Earth is a detriment to the galaxy.
但他损害了自己的利益 地球也在损害着银河的利益
What did you say?
你说什么?
You act out the same cycles of self-destruction again and again.
你们无数次实行着毁灭自己的行为
At this point your planet is the least civilized in the entire galaxy.
如今整个银河中你们的星球是文明程度最低的星球
- What did he say?  - He's saying we're a bunch of fuck-ups.
- 他说什么?  - 他说我们是一群该死的蠢货
Hey, it's our basic human right to be fuck-ups.
做蠢货是我们的基本人权
This civilization was founded on fuck-ups. And you know what?
这个文明就是蠢货建立的 你知道吗?
- That makes me proud.  - And me!
- 我为此而骄傲  - 我也是!
What is it they say? "To err is..."
那句话怎么说来着? "人非圣贤"
"To err is human."
"人非圣贤孰能无过"
"To err is human," so, uh...
"人非圣贤孰能无过"所以 嗯...
We do not believe you speak for all humanity.
我们认为你们不能代表全体人类
You are but two men. Two drunk men.
你们只有两个人 两个醉鬼
Three drunk men!
三个醉鬼!
Stevie-baby!
史蒂文宝贝!
Enough! Enough, humans!
够了! 够了 人类!
Oh, you are in trouble now. It's only the fucking Three Musketeers.
哦 你麻烦大了 三个火枪手到齐了
You are revolting against the wisdom of countless solar systems.
你们这是要背叛无数星系的智慧生命
Yeah, we are revolting!
没错 我们就是要背叛!
You just said you're not here to conquer. Can I just ask,
你刚刚说你不是来征服的 让我问问你
how many people did you have to replace in Newton Haven?
你在纽顿海文替换掉了多少人?
- That is irrelevant.  - Is it?
- 与此无关  - 是吗?
Hands up. Who here is human?
举手 这里谁是人类?
- I'm human.  - One!
- 我是  - 一个!
- And me.  - That's two.
- 还有我  - 两个
I am. But don't know for how long.
我也是 但不知道还能做多久
- Basil!  - Shh...
- 巴希尔!  - 嘘...
So what's that? Three? You had to replace an entire town?
怎么样? 三个人? 你把整个镇的人都替换了?
Not the entire town.
不是整个镇
Everybody apart from old Nutbowl and the Shifty twins.
包括纳特博尔和谢夫迪双胞胎的所有人
That's a good name for a band, Gary. You should write that down.
这名字用在乐队上不错啊 加里 你该记下来
I will. What about the ones you replaced,
我会的 那你替换掉的那些人呢
like Peter and Oliver?
皮特和奥利弗他们?
Yeah, what happened to the empties?
这些废容器你们怎么处理了?
I told you not to ask that!
告诉过你别问这个!
Redundant vessels are recycled, mulched and converted into fertilizer,
废容器被回收利用转化为肥料
whereupon they are returned to the earth to promote verdancy and growth.
他们被归还给土壤用于绿化
It is a highly efficient means of organic renewal.
这是非常高效的有机物回收利用手段
Mulched?
做肥料?
It is a relative few in light of our long-term plan.
根据我们的长远规划 这只是一小部分
You mean a few hundred thousand turned to fucking compost?
你是说有那么几十万人被你们做成该死的农家肥了?
What about the other places? The penetration points.
那其他那些地方的人呢? 其他那些渗入点?
Are they as successful as Newton Haven?
都像纽顿海文这么成功吗?
Because I'm guessing we're not the only glitch in your system.
因为我觉得 你系统里不听话的人不止我们几个吧
It is true, The Network has been experiencing some difficulties.
是的 网络的确面对过一些挫折
I think you bit off more than you can chew with Earth, mate.
我猜你们觉得地球没有那么容易被搞定 对吧?
Yeah, 'cause we are more belligerent, more stubborn
没错 因为我们更好斗 更顽强
and more idiotic than you can possibly imagine,
比你想象的更白痴吧
and I am not just talking about Gary.
我不仅在说加里
Yeah, there's more than one Gary King.
是的 他这样的人还多得是
- But you said...  - I fucking know what I fucking said!
- 但你们说过...  - 我知道我说过什么!
Your reliance on profanity is a measure of your immaturity as a man and a species,
你们对亵渎的依赖说明了你们作为人或者是物种都是不成熟的
Why don't you just get in your rocket and fuck off back to Legoland, you cunts!
你干嘛不滚回你的火箭飞回你们的天国去呢 蠢货!
- Yeah! Stop fucking Starbucking us, man!  - Yeah!
- 对! 别想在这里开连锁店!  - 就是!
It is our duty to challenge you.
转化你们是我们的责任
Just leave us to our own devices, you intergalactic arseholes.
我们的事我们自己说了算 混账!
- You misunderstand.  - Shut up!
- 你们误会了  - 闭嘴!
- We are trying...  - Nobody's listening!
- 我们试图...  - 我不听我不听!
If you'd only...
如果你们...
Face it, we are the human race and we don't like being told what to do.
面对吧 我们是人类 我们不需要别人教我们怎么做
Just what is it that you want to do?
你们想要的到底是什么?
- We want to be free!  - Yeah.
- 我们想要自由!  - 没错
We want to be free to do what we want to do!
我们想要为所欲为!
Yeah.
就是
- We want to get loaded.  - Yeah.
- 我们要喝醉  - 没错
And we want to have a good time.
想玩个痛快
And that's what we're going to do.
我们就是这样
It is pointless arguing with you.
简直是对牛弹琴
You will be left to your own devices.
你们自己做主吧
Really?
真的?
Yeah.
是的
Fuck it.
操
They fucked off.
他们熄火了
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Up yours! Up yours! Up yours!
耶 耶 耶 顶你! 你! 还有你!
Yeah, we did it! We won, we won!
耶 成功了 我们赢了!
Gary, let's Boo-Boo.
加里 快闪吧
Yeah, it's shit here, isn't it?
这里要毁了 是吧?
Oi, up here!
喂 从这走!
Go!
走!
Get up.
上去
Come on!
快点!
Well done.
干得好
Thanks a bunch. Had to go and spoil it, didn't you?
太谢谢你了 享受胜利的果实吧?
Yeah, happy now?
高兴了吧现在?
Basil, what do we do now?
巴希尔 现在做什么?
Same as before.
跟以前一样
Go!
跑!
Where's The Beast?
野兽呢?
The Beast is dead, mate.
野兽牺牲了 哥们
You know what... You know what's really annoying?
知道吗... 知道什么事让我不爽吗?
What?
什么?
I promised myself I wouldn't die in this town.
我发誓不要死在这里的
You're not gonna.
你不会的
I think our luck just changed.
我们已经转运了
Whoo-hoo!
呜呼!
Oh!
噢!
Sorry!
不好意思!
- Sam?  - Yes.
- 山姆?  - 是我
You came back for us!
你回来救我们了!
Yes, I did. Well, I got lost on the ring road. But, yes.
没错 其实我是在环路上迷路了 但我确实回来了
Hi, Sam, could you give us a lift to London, please?
嗨 山姆 捎我们去伦敦好吗?
Did you find out what happened to my brother?
我哥哥到底怎么样了?
We'll tell you on the way.
路上再跟你说
Sorry about the mess. I've been meaning to clear that up.
对不起有点乱 我本想回头弄干净的
- We forgive you. Let's go.  - Which way?
- 原谅你了 快走  - 朝哪?
Backwards!
朝后!
Which way now?
现在朝哪?
Go straight over!
直走!
We can make it.
我们能做到
We're gonna make it.
我们就要做到了
We made it!
我们成功了!
I'm sorry.
对不起
I know.
我知道
Everyone remembers where they were
当整个地球失去灯光的时候
when the lights went out on Planet Earth.
每个人都记得当时自己在哪里
Me, Gary, Steven and Sam, we were standing right by the switch.
我 加里 史蒂文和山姆当时就站在开关旁边
I guess it was a big night for everyone.
我们一起度过了一个漫长的黑夜
That morning gave a whole new meaning to the word "hangover".
随之而来的清晨让"宿醉"这个词有了全新的定义
We decided to walk it off, all the way back to London,
我们决定散步解酒 一路走回了伦敦
but the headache didn't end there. It just went on and on.
但是头痛丝毫没有缓解 反而一直持续不断
Talk about the Big Smoke.
说起伦敦
When The Network went down, it triggered some kind of pulse,
当网络瘫痪时 造成了某种停顿
wiped out all our technology
使我们的技术化为乌有
and sent us here,
导致我们现在
back to the Dark Ages.
回到了黑暗中世纪
There were casualties, of course. I knew a few of them.
伤亡在所难免 我就知道不少
Some guy from work, my cousin Paul, Gary's mum.
一个同事 我表弟保罗 加里的妈妈
Nobody really knew how many we lost,
没人清楚我们到底死了多少人
because we never heard from the rest of the world again.
因为地球上的通信联系再也没恢复过
Everyone got cut off.
只留下无数的孤岛
It isn't easy now, but it is simpler.
的确很艰难 但也很简单
I'm back with the wife, which is something.
我妻子回到了我的身边 这是件好事
We decided our problems didn't seem as bad in the grand scheme of things,
我们一致认为我俩之间的事情与周围比起来微不足道
We all had to go organic in a big way, but if I'm honest,
我们只能吃天然食品 但说实话
I'm hard pressed to recall any processed foods I actually miss.
我真的很怀念那些垃圾食品
As for the blanks, well, a funny thing happened there.
而那些空壳 产生了一些有意思的变化
They woke up.
他们醒了
A week or so after The Network pulled out, they just sort of rebooted by themselves,
网络离开后大约一周 他们好像是自我启动了
tried to start afresh.
想要重新做人了
They seemed lost at first, children cut off from their parents,
一开始他们很迷茫 就像离开了父母的小孩子
abandoned, forgotten, looking for guidance, for someone to show them the way.
被抛弃 被遗忘 寻求指引 希望得到帮助
I felt a bit sorry for them, to be honest.
说实话 对它们我感到有点内疚
The Network was right about one thing.
网络说对了一件事
We can be a bit uncivilized.
我们真的是不怎么文明
Maybe we would've been a bad influence on the rest of the galaxy.
也许已经对银河的其他世界造成了恶劣的影响
Oliver went back to being an estate agent.
奥利弗重新做了房产销售
People still need a roof over their heads,
人们仍然需要房屋遮风避雨
and the old Ollie always had a gift for the gab.
老奥利一向很能扯淡
I guess the new one has, too.
我估计他的替代品继承了这一点
He's doing all right.
他干得很不错
I hear that the Peter found his way home to Bishop's Gardens.
我听说皮特回到了毕肖普花园的家
I suppose he picked up where the other one left off.
估计是被别人遗弃后他又占了回来
I'm not sure his wife noticed.
不知他老婆有没有注意到
Maybe she chose not to. He's a pretty good dad by all accounts.
估计只是佯装不知吧 他是个好父亲
Steven and Sam got together in the end.
史蒂文和山姆在一起了
Didn't see that coming.
完全不在乎世界的现状
They shacked up just outside London.
他们住在伦敦城外的棚屋里
It's a pretty nice shack, too.
棚屋也相当不错
As for Gary? I don't know what happened to Gary.
至于加里? 不知道加里怎么样了
We got separated and I never saw him again.
自从分手后再没见过他
Some say he went back to Newton Haven. I don't know why.
据说他回到了纽顿海文 不知道为什么
I think his business there was done.
我觉得他在那里也没事可做
It's funny, but I miss him.
很有意思 但我很想他
I wonder if he misses me. Misses the boys.
不知他是不是想我 想我们
Wherever he is, I hope he's happy.
不论在哪里 我希望他快乐
That's all he ever wanted, really.
那是他最看重的东西
To have a good time.
玩个痛快
I just hope he found it beyond the bottom of a glass.
希望他可以在酒杯以外的地方找到快活
Because real happiness, real friends, those are things worth living for,
因为真的幸福 真的朋友 才是生活的意义
worth fighting for.
是值得为之奋斗的东西
Blank bastards.
混蛋空壳
Fucking robots.
该死的机器人
Five waters, please.
五杯水 谢谢
You can have one.
你可以要一杯
But I ain't serving this scum.
这些杂碎我不招待
Well, I'm afraid it's all for one and one for all.
我觉得应该人人为我 我为人人
You see, my young friends and I are on an adventure.
你瞧 我和我的小伙伴一起冒险
A quest, if you will. And since we find ourselves in need of refreshment,
完成某个任务 如果我们需要点刺激的话
you, sir, have the honor of drawing first blood.
你 先生 你将为此付出血的代价
So, I'll ask you again,
所以 我再说一遍
for the last time,
最后一遍
five waters, please.
五杯水 谢谢
Who the hell do you think you are?
你他妈以为自己是谁?
Me? They call me The King.
我? 他们管我叫老金
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 初见 咳嗽的小鱼 RK翔 汐颜 Mabb
校对: Mabb